MAN: Police Constable Nicholas Angel. Born and schooled in London.
尼古拉斯·天使巡警 出生並受教於倫敦
Graduated Canterbury University in 1993 with a double first in politics and sociology.
1993年畢業於坎特伯雷大學 成績優秀，獲得政治和社會雙學位
Attended Hendon College of Police Training.
之後在海頓警校接受培訓
Displayed great aptitude in field exercises.
在實戰方面顯示出相當的天賦
Notably, urban pacification and riot control.
尤其是平定城市暴亂方面
Back off!
退後！
Academically excelled in theoretical course work and final year examinations.
在校期間理論課成績和年終測評均為優
Received the Baton of Honour.
被授予榮譽警棍
Graduated with distinction into the Metropolitan Police Service.
後以優異成績畢業進入市警局
Quickly established an effectiveness and popularity within the community.
在社區中迅速樹立起自己的威望
Use your brain.
動動你們的腦子
Proceeded to improve skill base with courses in advanced driving
通過高級駕駛術和騎車術的課程
and advanced cycling.
提升了業務技能
Became heavily involved in a number of extra vocational activities.
深入參與了多項業餘活動
To this day holds the Met record for the 100 metre dash.
至今還保持著警局內百米記錄
In 2001 began active duty with the renowned SO 19 armed response unit.
2001年進入著名的第19特別行動 武裝快速反應部隊
Received a bravery award for efforts in the resolution of Operation Crackdown.
在「壓迫」行動中被授予勇氣勳章
In the last 12 months has received nine special commendations.
在過去12個月裡9次獲得特別表彰
Achieved the highest arrest record for any officer in the Met.
創造了警局內最高逮捕記錄
And sustained three injuries in the line of duty.
執勤時共負傷3次
Most recently in December when wounded by a man dressed as Father Christmas.
最近的一次是12月 被一名打扮成聖誕老人的男子刺傷
- Hello, Nicholas. - Hello, Sergeant.
- 你好，尼古拉斯 - 你好，警官
- How's the hand? - Still a bit stiff.
- 手怎麼樣了？ - 還有點僵
It can get awfully hairy out there.
這樣子出去可是很危險的
I'm surprised you werert snapped up sooner for a nice desk job. That's what I did.
你怎麼沒立即要求轉作文職 像我這樣
I prefer to think my office is out on the street.
我更喜歡出去巡邏
Indeed, you do.
我看也是
Your arrest record is 400% higher than any other officer.
你的逮捕記錄比同行要高4倍
Which is why it's high time that such skills were put to better use.
現在正是你大展拳腳的時候了
- We're making you Sergeant. - I see.
- 我們提升你做警官 - 明白
In Sandford, Gloucestershire.
分配到格洛斯特郡的沙福德村
- In where, sorry? - In Sandford, Gloucestershire.
- 分配到…哪兒？ - 格洛斯特郡的沙福德
- That's in the country. - Yes, lovely.
- 那是鄉下啊 - 沒錯，很漂亮
Isn't there a Sergeant's position here in London?
在倫敦就沒有個警官的空位？
No.
沒有
- Can I remain here as a PC? - No.
- 能不能還留在這當警員？ - 不行
- Do I have any choice in this?
- 難道沒選擇餘地了？ - 米有
Sergeant, I kind of like it here.
警官，我很喜歡這兒
Well, you've always wanted to transfer to the country.
你不一直都想要轉到鄉下去？
- In 20 years or so, yes. - Well done, you.
- 20年後，是的 - 那就得了
Hang on, I don't remember telling you that.
等等，我不記得和你講過這個
Yes, you did. You said,
不，你說過的
"I'd love to settle down in the country sometime, Janine."
「我想什麼時候到鄉下定居，珍妮」
I'd like to talk to the Inspector.
我要找督察談話
You can speak to the Inspector, but I can promise you
行啊，但我可以向你保證
he will tell you exactly the same thing as I have.
他講的會和我完全一樣
- Hello, Nicholas. How's the hand? - It's still a bit stiff.
- 你好，尼古拉斯，手怎麼樣了？ - 還有點僵
- And how are things at home? - I'm sorry, sir?
- 家裡怎麼樣？ - 什麼？
How's Janine?
珍妮怎麼樣？
We're no longer together, sir.
我們分了，長官
- Right. Then where are you living? - He's staying at the Section House, sir.
- 那你現在住哪？ - 他住在單元屋，長官
- With the recruits? - Yes, he's living out of cardboard boxes.
- 和新兵在一起？ - 他快沒紙盒了
Well, then, you're packed already.
那你已經打好包了？
Nicholas, we're offering you a smashing position with a delightful cottage,
尼古拉斯，我們給你的是份要職 並附一座舒適鄉村小屋
I don't know how many times. It'll be good for you.
都不記得有多少次了 很適合你的
- I don't really know what to say. - Yes?
- 我真不知道該說什麼了 - 遵命？
Yes, thank you.
遵命，謝謝？
No, I'm sorry. I'm gonna have to...
不，抱歉，我要…
- You want to take this higher? - Yes, yes, I do.
- 你要跟更上層的談？ - 是，是的
You want me to bother the Chief Inspector with this?
你想我去拿這件事煩督察長？
Yes.
是的
You want me to get the Chief Inspector to come all the way down here?
你要我去讓督察長大老遠到樓下來？
- Yes, I do. - Okay.
- 是的 - 好吧
Kenneth!
肯尼斯！
- Hello, Nicholas. How's the hand? - Still a bit stiff.
- 你好，尼古拉斯，手怎麼樣了？ - 還有點僵
- Chief Inspector... - Keep your seat.
- 督察長… - 請坐
Now, I know what you're going to say,
我知道你想說什麼
but the fact is, you've been making us all look bad.
但事實是你讓我們很沒面子
I'm sorry, sir?
什麼？
Of course we all appreciate your efforts,
我們當然欣賞你的付出
but you've been rather letting the side down.
但你讓我們在拖你後腿
It's all about being a team player, Nicholas.
我們需要的是團隊精神，尼古拉斯
You can't be the Sheriff of London.
倫敦可不是你一個人的
If we let you carry on running round town,
如果再讓你出去巡邏
you'll continue to be exceptional and we can't have that.
我們可受不了你這樣出色的表現
You'll put us all out of a job.
不然就要砸自己的飯碗了
With respect, sir.
恕我冒犯，長官
- You can't just make people disappear. - Yes, I can. I'm the Chief Inspector.
- 你不能就這麼讓人消失 - 我能的，我是督察長
Well, however you spin this, there's one thing you haven't taken into account.
不管你怎麼說，你忘了一件重要的事…
And that's what the "team" is gonna make of this.
那就是「團隊合作精神」
- Hello? - ANGEL: Janine, it's me.
- 喂？ - 珍妮，是我
I know. I'm at work.
知道，我在工作呢
I know, I'm outside.
知道，我就在外面
What's the situation?
情況如何？
You know the situation. We've been over this.
明知故問，我們已經談過了
No, I... I meant here.
不，我是指這裡
Two people involved, distinct signs of a struggle.
一共兩人，有明顯的搏鬥痕跡
Complete mess.
很亂
- You are talking about here? - Nicholas, what do you want?
- 你不是在說我們？ - 尼古拉斯，你想怎麼樣？
Well, I have something important to tell you and I didn't wanna do it over the phone.
我有些重要的事情想跟你說 但是我又不想在電話裡說
Janine, I've been transferred. I'm moving away for a while.
珍妮，我被調職了 我要搬走一段時間
I'm not Janine.
我不是珍妮
Janine, I've been transferred. I'm moving away for a while.
珍妮，我被調職了 我要搬走一段時間
I know. Bob told me.
我知道，鮑勃跟我說了
Hello, there.
你好
Well, I wanted to tell you in person.
我要親口跟你說
And there's no reason we can't be civil with each other.
沒有理由我們不能再和平相處
It's not that long ago we were talking about getting married.
不久前我們不還說過要結婚嗎？
Yes, but you were already married to the force, werert you?
是啊 但你已經嫁給了治安機關，不是嗎？
We're actually supposed to call it "the service" now.
事實上，我們現在稱之為治安部門
Official vocab guidelines state that "force" is too aggressive.
官方指南稱「機關」太具侵略性了
See. It's only ever about the job.
看見沒，一直只是關於工作的事
- It's all you care about. - That's not true.
- 你只關心工作 - 不是這樣的
No, you're right, you do have that rubber plant.
是啊，你還有一盆塑膠花
- It's a Japanese Peace Lily. - You just can't switch off, Nicholas.
- 那是日本白鶴芋 - 你放不下工作，尼古拉斯
And until you find a person you care about more than your job, you never will.
除非你能找到比你工作更重要的人 但那可能嗎？
Besides, you were the one who suggested we take a break.
還有，是你提出分手的
Yes, well, guilty people often make the first move.
是啊，罪人總是會先行一步的
Actually, there's something I need to tell you.
實際上，我有些事情要跟你說
- You're seeing someone else. - Yes. How did you...
- 你在和別人約會？ - 是啊，你怎麼…？
- Is it Bob? - No.
- 和鮑勃？ - 不是
Does Bob look like the kind of person I'd go out with?
鮑勃看上去是我喜歡的類型嗎？
It's Dave.
是戴夫
Hello, there.
你好
I see.
我明白了
Oh, Nicholas.
噢，尼古拉斯
You do realise that window was broken from the inside?
你發現那窗戶是從裡面打破的吧？
I'm just calling with details of your accommodation.
我打電話來告訴你住宿的詳情
We've got you a lovely little cottage on Spencer Hill.
我們在斯賓塞山 給你準備了個舒適的村舍 [警察英勇開槍救人]
Look forward to meeting you anon. Cheerio.
期待能盡快見到你，回見
Nicholas, Frank again. One other thing about your cottage.
尼古拉斯，還是我弗蘭克 還是關於你得宿舍
It's not ready.
房子沒準備好
It would appear the heavens have opened.
似乎天空放晴了
- I was hoping to check in. - Check in?
- 我來登記住宿 - 登記住宿？
But you've always been here.
但你一直都住這裡啊
- Excuse me? - Oh, I'm sorry.
- 什麼？ - 啊，對不起
I thought you were my husband.
我還以為你是我丈夫呢
- You must be Sergeant Angel. - Yes, I am.
- 你一定是天使警官了 - 是的，我是
I'm Joyce Cooper. I trust you had a pleasant trip. Fascist.
我是喬伊絲·箍桶匠 您的旅行還愉快，法西斯分子
I beg your pardon?
什麼？
"System of Government characterised by extreme dictatorship." Seven across.
「極端專政的政府體系」 第七橫行 [她在玩填字遊戲]
- Oh, I see. It's "fascism." - Fascism. Wonderful.
- 啊，我明白了，是法西斯主義 - 法西斯主義，太棒了
Now, we've put you in the Castle Suite. Bernard will escort you up there.
我們把你安排在城堡套房 伯納德會帶你上去的
Well, actually, I could probably make my own way up. Hag.
呃，我自己就能上去，母夜叉
I beg your pardon?
什麼？
"Evil old woman considered frightful or ugly." It's 12 down.
「可怕或醜陋的邪惡老女人」 第12豎行
Oh, bless you.
啊， 祝福你
- Pint of lager, please, Mary. - MARY: Right you are, my love.
- 來一杯啤酒，瑪麗 - 就來，親愛的
Yes, sir, what can I get you?
先生，想要點什麼？
Could I have a glass of the cranberry juice, please?
能來一杯酸果蔓汁嗎？
Certainly.
當然
Now, you wouldn't, by any chance, be the new policeman?
你不會是新來的警察吧？
Police officer, yes. I'm Nicholas Angel.
是的，我叫尼古拉斯·天使
- I'm Roy Porter. This is my wife Mary. - Mary.
- 我叫羅伊·黑啤，這是我妻子瑪麗 - 我是瑪麗
MARY: Welcome to Sandford.
歡迎來到沙福德
If there's anything you need, just let us know.
如果想要什麼，儘管跟我們說
Thank you. Could I borrow your newspaper?
謝謝，能借報紙看看嗎？
It's not ours, love.
這不是我們的，親愛的
We're not big fans of the local fish wrapper, are we, Mare?
我們才不看這種包裝紙 是吧，瑪麗？
- They listed her age as 55. - When I'm actually 53.
- 上面說她的年齡是55 - 可我實際上才53
Fifty-three.
是53
- Pint of lager, please, Mary. - Right you are, my love.
- 再來一杯啤酒，瑪麗 - 就來，親愛的
- Excuse me. - What?
- 你 - 怎麼了？
- Whers your birthday? - Twenty-second of February.
- 你的生日是幾月幾號？ - 2月22號
- What year? - Every year.
- 哪一年？ - 每年
Get out.
出去
- Whers your birthday? - Eighth of May, 1969.
- 你什麼時候生的 - 1969年5月8號
- You're 37? - Yeah.
- 你37歲？ - 是啊
Get out.
出去
Whers your birthday?
你的生日呢？
- Is there a problem, Officer? - Yes, there is, Mr Porter.
- 有問題嗎，警官？ - 是的，黑啤先生
It would appear a number of your patrons are under age.
你的一部分客人未到法定年齡
Well, a few of them may be a month or two south of proper.
有幾個還有一兩個月就到了
But if they're in here, it stops them getting into trouble out there.
他們在這裡的話 就不會在外面惹麻煩了
Yeah, the way we see it, it's all for the greater good.
這樣子做是為了村莊好
The greater good.
為了村莊好
Well, that's as may be, but the law's the law and they'll have to go.
也許是這樣 但法律就是法律，他們必須走
- Another cranberry juice? - I'm fine, thank you.
- 再來杯酸果蔓汁？ - 不用了，謝謝
I hope you're not planning on driving that.
你不會在打算開這部車
No.
麼有
Right. I'm taking you to the station.
好啊，我要把你帶到局裡去
Where is it?
警察局在哪？
What?
幹嘛？
ANGEL: Move.
進去
"Nicholas Angel."
尼古拉斯·天使
- Oh, when did you start? - Tomorrow.
- 什麼時候開始上班的？ - 明天
Well, I see you've already arrested the whole village.
我想你已經把全村的人都抓來了
Not exactly.
沒那麼多
- You in for the night? - Go on, four's free.
- 進來呆一晚嗎？ - 去吧，4號房是空的
- Hey, now, I need to speak to him. - He'll be no use till the morning.
- 嘿，我現在要跟他談談 - 不到明早他是不會清醒的
I see.
明白了
You really want to process all this lot?
你真的要處理這些人嗎？
- My pers running out. - Not a problem.
- 我的筆沒油了 - 不是問題
- Morning, Sergeant. - Morning.
- 早上好，警官 - 早上好
Morning.
早上好
Morning, Sergeant.
早上好，警官
- Lock me up. - I'm sorry?
- 關我進牢房吧 - 什麼？
I'm a slasher and I must be stopped.
我要繼續砍，你得阻止我
- You're a what? - A slasher of prices.
- 你要什麼？ - 砍價的砍
Just kidding. I'm Simon Skinner. I run the local supermarché>
開個玩笑，我是西蒙·扒皮 經營著當地的超市
Drop in and see me sometime. My discounts are criminal.
有空順路來看看我 我在違規打折
Catch me later!
來捉我吧！
Morning, Sergeant.
早上好，警官
Could you tell the Inspector I've arrived, please?
告訴督察我已經來了，好嗎？
No.
不行
Why?
為什麼？
He's not in yet.
他還沒來
- Well, how's our guest? - Guest?
- 我們的客人怎麼樣了？ - 客人？
- The inebriate in cell four. - I don't know. Nobody tells me nothing.
- 四號監的醉漢 - 我不知道，沒人跟我講過
Can I get cell four open, please?
能打開四號監嗎？
Danny, can you open four?
胖子，能把四號打開嗎？
- He's gone. - Oh, my God. Who's gone?
- 他逃跑了 - 啊，我的天，誰跑了？
- Why are you dressed like a police officer? - Because I am one.
- 你為什麼穿得跟警察一樣？ - 我本來就是
Sergeant Angel, at last. Frank Butterman.
天使警官，終於來了 我是弗蘭克·黃油男
- I see you've already met my boy. - Yes.
- 我想你已經見過我的兒子了 - 是啊
FRANK: Do forgive me. I'm something of a Wild West nut.
請諒解我，我有幾分是個西部迷
Speaking of which, that was a fair few outlaws you rounded up last night.
說起來，昨晚你制止了不少非法行為
Thank you, sir.
謝謝，長官
I admire your enthusiasm and far be it from me to stifle your flair,
我很欽佩你的激情 跟著我你真是太屈才了
but this isn't London. Oh, yes, please, Danny.
但這裡不是倫敦 啊，好的，丹尼
With respect, sir,
恕我冒犯，長官
geographical location shouldn't factor in the application of the law.
地理位置因素並不影響法律的實行
No, thanks.
不用，謝謝
Statistically, Sandford is the safest village in the country.
據統計，沙福德是國內最安全的村莊
But that doesn't mean it requires anything less
但這並不表明 我們可以不謹慎盡責，魯莽行事
There's a reason we accommodate a few of the younglings at the pub.
我們允許一些年輕人進酒館是有原因的
- The greater good? - The greater good. Precisely.
- 為了村莊好？ - 為了村莊好，太對了
Your predecessor assumed that rural policing was easy.
你的前任認為維持鄉下治安很容易
Ended up having a nervous breakdown.
最終卻因精神緊張而崩潰
And Sergeant Popwell was an exceptional officer, truly exceptional.
冒泡警官曾是名傑出的警察 真的很傑出
And he had one thing you haven't got.
他還有件你所不具備的東西
- What's that, sir? - A great big bushy beard.
是什麼，長官？
Come on, let's have a mosey around.
快來，帶你轉一下
Locker room.
存物櫃房
Riot room.
防暴裝備房
Evidence room.
證物房
Now, how about a trip to the Andes?
現在，去安第斯山玩一趟怎麼樣？
Detective Sergeant Wainwright and Detective Constable Can'twright.
寫不來偵探警官，和 不會寫偵探巡警
Don't get up.
不用起身了
I expect you're wondering why we call them the Andes.
我想你一定很好奇 為什麼稱他們為安第斯山
- They're both called Andrew? - They said you were good.
- 他們都叫安德魯？（音近安第斯山） - 果然厲害啊
Also, because talking to them is an uphill struggle, isn't it, Dad?
還有，跟他們談話就跟 登山一樣費力，是吧，父親？
- Fuck off! - Thank you, Danny.
- 操死你們！ - 謝謝你，丹尼
And this is where it all happens.
這裡就是辦事的地方
That is Sergeant Tony Fisher.
那是托尼·漁夫警官
PC Bob Walker.
鮑勃·步行者警員
And that is Saxon.
還有那是撒克遜
And this is one Doris Thatcher.
這是多瑞絲·茅屋匠
- She's our only policewoman. - She's not a policewoman.
- 她是我們唯一的女警察 - 她不是女警察
- Yeah, she is. I've seen her bra. - She's a police officer.
- 是的，她是啊，我見過她的胸罩 - 她是名警務人員
Being a woman has nothing to do with it.
和是不是女性沒有關係
Oh, I don't know. Comes in handy every so often.
那些我不清楚 但我還是偶爾能派得上用場的
I could've given you the tour. I've been round the station a few times.
我可以帶你走走 警察局我已經轉過好多次了
And what's upstairs?
樓上是什麼？
Well, well, well, I see we have visitors.
唔，看來我們有訪客了
Nicholas, this is Tom Weaver.
尼古拉斯，這是湯姆·織布工
Civilian liaison with the Neighbourhood Watch Alliance.
[鄰里監控聯盟]（簡稱NWA） 的聯絡員
You'll find that we run a very tight ship here.
你會發現我們是很有組織性的
From this command centre I can see what the whole village is up to.
從這個控制中心 我能看到整個村莊的情況
I must say I was rather admiring your handiwork last night.
我必須說我非常欽佩你昨晚的工作
It's a pity you didn't do the same to those bloody hoodies.
很遺憾你沒有對這些該死的帽子黨 採取同樣的行動
Hanging around. Loitering. Sitting.
到處閒逛，呆坐著虛度光陰
Actually, I did notice some minor graffiti on the fountain.
實際上，我確實注意到噴泉上 有些小的塗鴉
Graffiti? They've gotta be dealt with, Frank.
塗鴉？一定要處理他們，弗蘭克
They're nippers, Tom. They'll come round.
他們還是孩子，湯姆 他們消失的
Which reminds me,
這提醒了我
our friend, The Living Statue, was here on Saturday.
我們的朋友 「活雕像」週六來過這裡
11:00, 12:00, 1:00, 2:00.
11點，12點，1點，2點
If we don't come down hard on these clowns,
如果我們不對這些小丑 採取些嚴厲措施的話
- we are gonna be up to our balls in jugglers. - We'll get right onto it, Tom.
- 我們的球都要被他們玩沒了 - 我們會立馬處理的，湯姆
We like to let them think they run the place.
我們要讓他們覺得是他們掌控著這地方
Well, that's that.
唔，就這些了
Unless there's anything you're unclear about?
你還有什麼不明白的嗎？
Yes, sir. Why is everybody eating chocolate cake?
是的，長官 為什麼每個人都在吃巧克力蛋糕呢？
The Black Forest gateau is on Danny. As punishment for his little indiscretion.
黑森林奶油蛋糕是丹尼請的 作為他的小疏忽的懲罰
His...
他的…
Sir, I don't think driving under the influence can be called a "little indiscretion."
長官，我不認為醉酒駕車只是小疏忽
No, the gateau is for misplacing his helmet the other week.
不，蛋糕是他前周放錯了頭盔的懲罰
Last night's incident will require something rather more serious.
昨晚的事故當然要嚴肅處理
- Good. - Do you like ice-cream?
- 那就好 - 你喜歡吃冰淇淋嗎？
I'm sorry, sir, I don't follow.
對不起，長官，我不明白
Let's just say that we won't be short of Chunky Monkey for the next month.
我說那樣下個月我們就有 果仁冰激凌吃了
Dad.
老爸
Now, since it's your first day and it's 11:30, I'd say that's lunch.
既然你第一天上班，現在11點半 我說…去吃午飯吧
So, what made you choose Sandford then, Sergeant Angel?
那麼，是什麼讓你選擇了沙福德了 天使警官？
It wasrt actually my choice.
實際上不是我選的
Oh, right, right, wasrt your choice to come down here and tell me how to do my job.
明白，明白 不是你主動來這兒教我怎麼幹活的
Our jobs.
教我們怎麼幹…
ALL: Yeah.
是啊
Look, I can assure you it wasrt my intention to upset the apple can't.
聽著，我可以保證 我並不是來搶飯碗的
Yeah, 'cause we all sell apples round here, don't we?
是啊 我們都用盤子吃飯的，對不對？
- Your dad sells apples, Andy. - And raspberries.
- 你爸也是，安迪 - 還會用盆
I bet you can't wait to jump into Sergeant Popwell's grave.
我打賭你等不及 要跳進冒泡警官的棺材了
I'm not jumping into anyone's grave.
我不會跳進任何人的棺材
- You got a moustache. - I know.
- 你有…鬍子 - 我知道
- Why have you got your stab vest on? - It's a requirement.
- 你為什麼要防護背心？ - 這是必須的
In the city maybe. Nobody's gonna stab you in here, Sergeant.
也許在市裡面是這樣 但這裡沒人會想刺你的，警官
Not a member of the public anyhow.
絕對不會在這裡發生
- Have you been stabbed, Sergeant Fisher? - No.
- 你被刺傷過嗎，漁夫警官？ - 沒有
Well, I have.
我被刺過
And I can assure you it is not in the least bit amusing.
我向你保證刺人並不好玩
Have you seen a lot of action, Sergeant Angel?
你你見過別人執行任務嗎，天使警官？
I've experienced my fair share, yes.
我當時就在場，是的
- Did you cook any fools? - Excuse me?
- 你煮過一些蠢貨嗎？ - 什麼？
Did you shoot anybody?
你開槍射過人嗎？
He shot a crack head with a Kalashnikov.
他用克拉什尼科夫衝鋒鎗射過癮君子
- Where did you get that? - The offender had the Kalashnikov.
- 你從哪裡搞來那槍的？ - 是罪犯持有克拉什尼科夫衝鋒鎗
Where'd he get that?
他從那兒搞的？
You do know there are more guns in the country than there are in the city?
你應該知道鄉下比城裡有更多的槍吧？
Everybody and their mums is packing round here.
所有人和他們的老母都攜帶武器
- Like who? - Farmers.
- 比如？ - 農夫們
- Who else? - Farmers's mums.
- 還有呢？ - 他們的老娘
What's it like being stabbed?
被刺傷了是什麼感覺？
It was the single most painful experience of my life.
是我一生中最痛的經歷
What was the second most painful?
第二痛的呢？
No.
- 那你有沒有高速追蹤過罪犯？ - 嗯，有過
- Ever been in a high speed pursuit? - Yes, I have.
你有沒有在高速追蹤的同時射擊？
No.
沒
AMANDA ON WALKIE-TALKIE: Annette, that Sergeant Angel's coming into your shop.
安妮特，天使警官進了你的店
Get a look at his arse.
看他的屁股呀
- What about Lethal Weapon? - No.
- 《致命武器》呢？ - 沒
- You've seen Die Hard, though?
- 那你該看過《虎膽龍威》吧？
- Bad Boys II? - No.
- 《絕地戰警2》？ - 沒
You ain't seen Bad Boys II?
你沒看過《絕地戰警2》？
- Hell of a day, huh? - Yeah.
- 該死的一天，哈？ - 是啊
- Same again tomorrow?
- 明天照樣？
Amanda Paver, headmistress of Sandford Primary.
這是阿曼達·鋪路機 沙福德小學的校長
How do you do, Sergeant?
你好嗎，警官？
- Simon Skinner, I believe you've met. - Oh, we're already firm friends.
- 這是西蒙·扒皮，我想你已經見過 - 我們已經是好朋友了
Oh, please, please, come with me, will you?
啊，借過，跟我來，好嗎？
This is Leslie Tiller,
這是萊絲莉·耕種機
whose horticultural expertise has helped put Sandford on the map.
正是因為她的出色園藝 才使得沙福德聞名遐邇
- She's ever so good. - Oh, go on.
- 她一直都很棒 - 別胡說啦！
This is James Reaper, who owns Brannigan Farm.
這是詹姆斯·收割機，巴尼根農場的主人
I hear you're quite the marksman.
我聽說你是個神槍手
Perhaps you might like to join us for a shoot one day.
也許有天你能跟我們一起打獵
Well, I haven't held a firearm for over two years, Mr Reaper.
我已經有兩年多沒碰槍支了，收割機先生
I'd quite like to keep it that way.
我也希望能一直保持下去
You will be popular with the local birds.
當地的小鳥（妞）一定很喜歡你
Birds.
小鳥
Nicholas, hello. Reverend Shooter.
尼古拉斯，你好，我是射擊手牧師
I want to ask you, would you read a homily at Sunday Service?
我想知道週末做禮拜時你願意做布道嗎？
That might be a little hypocritical of me, Reverend.
那對我來說有點太偽善了，牧師
Oh, you're an atheist?
啊，你是個無神論者？
No, I'm... I'm...
不，我…我…
I'm open to the concept of religion, I'm just not entirely convinced by it.
我信奉宗教自由 我只是不能完全相信教義
- You're an agnostic? - I think I have a cream for that.
- 你是不可知論者？ - 我想我有種藥膏可以治一下
Robin Hatcher, our resident sawbones.
羅賓·孵化器，我們當地的醫生
Hopefully we won't see too much of each other over the coming months.
希望在接下來的日子裡我們不要常見面
Well, all that remains is to welcome you
還有就是歡迎你參加 鄰里監控聯盟的周會
Now, quick announcement before we begin.
會前的一個小通知
Janet Barker has just given birth to twins.
珍妮特·剝皮機生了一對雙胞胎
So, congratulations to her.
恭喜她
- Tom? - Thanks, Joyce.
- 該你了，湯姆？ - 謝謝，喬伊絲
Now.
現在
I am sure that all of you will have noticed the return of a blight to our streets.
我肯定，你們都已經覺察到 我們的街道環境又在惡化
It's made all the more disturbing as the Village of the Year contest looms.
這會破壞競爭年度最佳村莊的計劃
I refer, of course, to the extremely irritating Living Statue.
我所說的 就是那極討人厭的「活雕像」
ANGEL: Police work is as much about preventing crime
警察的工作與其說是打擊犯罪 不如說是預防犯罪
Most importantly, it is about procedural correctness
最重要的是 它是將道德權威以正確的程序加以實施
Any questions?
還有問題嗎？
Yes.
說
Is it true that there is a place in a mars head
人的頭有一個部位 如果射中那個地方，頭會爆嗎？
Hi, hi, Tim Messenger.
嗨嗨，我是提姆·情報員
Can I get a quick shot for the Sandford Citizen?
我可以為《沙福德公民報》拍張照嗎？
Okay.
好的
How about you put the teacher in handcuffs?
拍張你把老師拷起來的照片怎麼樣？
I don't think that gives off the right signals.
我想那會誤導群眾
Too cheesy-pie. Okay. Gotcha.
太瀟灑了，好的，聽你的
- Give the little blonde kid your hat. - I'd rather not.
- 把帽子給你旁邊的小女孩？ - 還是不了吧
- Wave your hitting stick about. - No.
- 四處揮舞你的警棍呢？ - 不
Righty-ho-ho.
好吧
Oh, can I have your autograph, please?
你能簽個名嗎？
- For the breakfast. - Oh, sorry.
- 是早餐的 - 啊，對不起
Hey, that werert me.
嘿，不關我事
- Morning, Angle. - Good morning, Angle.
- 早，天吏 - 早上好，天吏
- Sergeant Angel. - STAKER: Morning. The swars escaped.
- 我是天使警官 - 早上好，天鵝跑掉了
- The swars escaped? - Yeah.
- 天鵝跑掉了 - 嗯
Right. And where has the swan escaped from exactly?
好的，天鵝具體是從哪裡跑掉了？
- The castle. - Oh, yeah? And who might you be?
- 城堡 - 是嗎？你是哪位？
Mr Staker. Yeah, Mr Peter lan Staker.
史泰克先生，彼得·伊恩·史泰克先生
P. I. Staker. Right. Piss taker. Come on!
彼·伊·史泰克，對吧 鼻屎，拜託！
Yes, Mr Staker. We'll do everything we can. Can you describe it to me?
是的，史泰克先生，我們會盡全力的 能向我描敘一下外貌嗎？
It's about two foot tall.
大概有兩英尺高
- Long slender neck. - Yeah.
- 細長的脖子 - 嗯
- Kind of orange and black bill. - Anything else?
- 有點黑黃色的喙 - 還有呢？
Well, it's a swan.
反正，是只天鵝
That's just gonna scare it.
會嚇著它的
- No luck catching them swans then? - It's just the one swan, actually.
- 那些天鵝可不好抓啊？ - 實際上只有一隻
- Want anything from the shop? - You've just been to the shop.
- 想去店裡買點什麼嗎？ - 你不剛去過嗎？
I was thinking of a different shop.
我是指其他店
Constable Butterman, this is not the time for personal errands.
黃油男巡警 現在可不是忙私事的時候
- Well, there's nothing going on, is there? - There is always something going on.
- 現在不是沒什麼狀況嘛？ - 總會有狀況的
You have to look closer, all right? What about this guy?
你必須要加倍小心，明白？ 比如這傢伙？
- Mr Treacher? - Yeah.
- 叛徒先生？ - 嗯
Why has he got that big coat on?
他為什麼要穿件大外套？
He can't be cold. Why the extra layer? Maybe he's trying to hide something.
他又不冷，為什麼要穿這麼多？ 也許他藏了些什麼東西
Mr Treacher?
叛徒先生？
Okay. What about this guy?
好吧，那這傢伙呢？
Ask yourself, why has he got his hat pulled down like that?
想想看，他為什麼要把帽子拉那麼低？
- He's fuck ugly. - Or he doesn't want you to see his face.
- 他是個醜八怪 - 或者他不想讓你看見他的臉
Because he's fuck ugly.
正因為他是個醜八怪
Okay, what's his story?
好吧，那他呢？
- Oh, that's Lurch. - Go on.
- 哦，那是傻大個 - 繼續說
- He's a trolley boy at the local supermarket. - Good.
- 他是當地超市的推車工 - 繼續
Real name, Michael Armstrong.
真名是邁克·粗手臂
- Dad says he's got a child's mind. - Okay.
- 父親說他弱智 - 嗯
And lives up Summer Street with his mum and his sister.
他跟她媽媽和妹妹一起住在夏日街
And are they as big as he is?
也跟他一樣強壯嗎？
- Who? - The mum and the sister.
- 誰？ - 他媽媽和妹妹
Same person.
都是同一個人
What shop were you thinking of?
你想去哪家店？
TINA ON PA: Sergeant Angel to the Manager's office.
天使警官請到經理室來
Manager's office. Sergeant Angel.
請到經理室來，天使警官
Sergeant Angel. Or is it Angle?
是天使警官，還是天吏？
Mr Skinner, a baby's sicked up in aisle six.
扒皮先生，有個嬰兒在6號走廊嘔吐了
Please excuse me. Michael!
不好意思 邁克爾！
Yarp.
好的
- Child vomit. Aisle six. Mop it up. - Yarp.
- 6號走廊有嘔吐物，去拖乾淨了 - 好的
- Mr Skinner, is there a problem? - No, no, no, no.
- 扒皮先生，有什麼麻煩嗎？ - 沒，沒有
I simply wanted to say how lovely it is to see you supporting your local store.
我只是想說能看到你 支持本地商舖真是太好了
Well, that's quite all right.
那是應該的
All too many have defected to the big Megamart in Buford Abbey.
有許多人都跑到布福德·艾比的 超級商業中心去購物了
May their heads be struck from their shoulders for such disloyalty.
這麼不忠的客人 真該砍了他們的腦袋
Yes, well, I am on duty, so if you'll excuse me.
好了，我正在執勤 請恕我失陪
Of course. I simply spied you loitering in organic produce
當然了，我看你你一直 在有機食品旁閒逛
and assumed you had time on your hands.
就想當然地以為你的時間很充裕
Well, maybe I'm not the one you should be keeping an eye on.
也許你應該監視一下其他人
That's the Fridge Magnate. His name's George Merchant.
那是電冰箱大王 他名叫喬治·批發商
Made a fortune in kitchen goods. Built that monstrosity on Norris Avenue.
靠經營廚具發了財 卻在諾裡斯街上蓋怪房
Actually, I wasrt talking about him.
其實，我沒在說他
I was talking about him.
我指的是他
Excuse me.
失陪了
(DANNY READING)
《超級警察》
"Meet the cop that can't be stopped."
所向披靡的警察
MAN: Tosser!
臭小子！
Trouble in the high street.
主幹道有情況
Sergeant Angel's having a spot of bother.
天使警官有了點小麻煩
Roger that.
收到
MAN: Morning, Sergeant.
早，警官
You mothers.
你他媽的
- Let's cut through here. Head him off. - Through the gardens?
- 我們從這裡穿過去，截他的道 - 穿過花園？
What's the matter, Danny? You never taken a shortcut before.
怎麼了，胖子？ 你從來沒抄過小道？
Hey, give me that!
嘿，把那給我！
"You do not have to say anything, however it may harm your defence
你有權保持沉默
"Anything you do say can be given in evidence."
你所說的一切都將作為呈堂證供
- Hi, Danny. - All right, Pete?
- 嗨，胖子 - 怎樣，彼得？
Do you know this man?
你認識他？
Yeah, he's Auntie Jackie's sister's brother's boy.
嗯，他是安迪·傑姬的妹妹的 哥哥的兒子
And it didn't occur to you to mention this before?
以前怎麼沒聽你提起過？
Couldrt see his face, could I? I'm not made of eyes.
我不是看不見他的臉嗎？ 我又不是透視眼
Impressive collar.
幹得漂亮
Shame Mr Skinner doesn't want to press charges.
可惜扒皮先生不想起訴
What do you mean, he doesn't wanna press charges?
什麼意思 他不想起訴？
I'm simply suggesting that, you know, Peter be given a second chance
我只是覺得在彼得提高犯罪率之前 應該再給他次機會
I'm sure he's going to learn a valuable lesson.
我確信這對他來說是次寶貴的教訓
- Stealing biscuits is wrong? - Correct.
- 偷餅乾是大錯？ - 就是嘛
Thanks.
謝謝
And yet we respond by not taking a single punitive measure?
那我們就不採取任何懲罰性措施？
Well, that's the way the cookie crumbles.
瞧，曲奇不已經碎了嘛
Like the biscuits, isn't it?
餅乾也是，是吧？
- Mr Skinner... - Is everything all right?
- 扒皮先生… - 一切都還好吧？
Well, sir, Mr Skinner feels it would be better not to prosecute an individual
長官，扒皮先生不希望起訴 一名已經犯過罪的人
Leave this with me.
我來接手吧
I'll make sure everyone gets their just deserts.
我一定會給大家個滿意的交代
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Twenty-seven.
27KM/H
- DANNY: Have you ever seen Point Break? - No.
- 你看過《終極豪情》嗎？ - 沒
Amazing bit in Point Break where they jump over fences.
在電影裡的 他們跳過柵欄時的樣子太酷了
Is there now? Twenty-nine.
是嗎？29KM/H
Patrick Swayze's just robbed this bank and Keanu Reeves is chasing him
帕特裡克· 斯韋茲剛搶銀行 基努·裡維斯穿過公園去追捕他
and he's firing his gun up in the air, he's like...
他朝天開了槍，他就像這樣…啊~~~
Forty.
40KM/H
Have you ever fired your gun up in the air and gone...
你有沒有朝天開過槍然後狂叫？
No, I have not ever fired my gun up in the air and gone...
沒有，我從沒朝天開過槍，也沒狂叫
Thirty.
30KM/H
Sorry, I... I just... I just feel like I'm missing out sometimes.
對不起，我只是有時覺得我白混了
- I wanna do what you do. - You do, do what I do.
- 我想跟你做同樣的事 - 你就在做我做的事
What on earth do you think you're missing out on?
你怎麼會覺得你白混了呢？
Gun fights. Car chases. Proper action and shit.
沒經歷過槍戰，汽車追逐戰 沒執行過什麼任務之類的
Police work is not about proper action or shit.
警察的工作不是大行動或之類的
Twenty-nine.
29KM/H
If you had paid attention to me in school,
如果你有認真聽 我在學校的演講的話
Fire up the roof.
拉響警燈
That was brilliant.
真是太帥了
Was I going a tad fast, Officer?
我開得有點快了嗎，長官？
Yes, you were, Mr Blower.
是啊，確實，吹牛皮先生
Well, now, you see, we are staging a homage
要知道，我們正在準備威廉姆·莎士比亞的 《羅密歐與朱麗葉》歌舞劇
I'm playing the eponymous hero, you see.
我扮演的是位英雄
Romeo not Juliet.
羅密歐，不是朱麗葉
- What are you writing? - Everything you're saying.
- 你在寫什麼？ - 你說的每一句話
I might need to refer to it later.
我以後可能會用的上
Now, Officer, I am a respected solicitor so there's no need to...
長官，我是名有地位的律師 所以沒必要…
Just stop writing, will you?
別寫了，好不好？
Look, I'm merely trying to explain why I might have exceeded the speed limit.
聽著，我只不過想解釋 我速度「快」的原因
You're playing the male lead in a homage to William Shakespeare's
你在莎士比亞的《羅密歐與朱麗葉》 歌舞劇擔任男主角
You think this is sufficient reason to travel at 48 in a 30 zone?
你覺得在限速30KM/H的道路上 開到48KM/H，這個理由充分嗎？
- Well, I... - To flout speed limits
- 唔，我… - 無視限速
- specifically put in place to save lives. - Just, look, this is preposterous.
- 尤其是至人民生命於不顧 - 豈有此理
- "Preposterous." - Look, just stop writing!
- 「豈有此理」 - 聽著，別寫了！
"Stop writing."
「別寫了」
Look, you're right, I apologise.
聽著，你是對的，我承認錯誤
- See what I did there? - You hypnotised him.
- 看見我怎麼做的了吧？ - 你忽悠了他
No, I used this.
不，我利用了這個
This is the most important piece of equipment you will ever own.
這是你所擁有的最重要的裝備
This notebook has saved my skin more times than I care to mention.
它已經不知道救過我多少次了
You should think about using yours more often.
你也該考慮多用用你的那本
- I do use mine. - Show me.
- 我當然在用了 - 給我看看
- That's just extraordinary. - You should see the one on the other side.
- 真是太有才了 - 你該再看看反面
- What are you up to tonight? - I have to water my Peace Lily.
- 今晚幹什麼？ - 給我的白鶴芋澆水
Thought you might wanna do something.
你肯定有想要做的事
- What exactly were you thinking? - Don't know. Pub?
- 你到底在打什麼主意？ - 不知道，去酒館？
I don't think that's a good idea. Do you?
我覺得那不是個好主意，你呢？
You two.
你們兩個
A Mr Blower left you tickets for Romeo and Juliet tonight.
吹牛皮先生給你們留了今晚 《羅密歐與朱麗葉》的票
Said it was by way of an apology.
說是想略表歉意
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 是嗎？ - 嗯
Well, we can't accept gifts from somebody we've officially rebuked. So...
我們不能接受一名 有公務往來的人的禮物，所以…
Yeah.
是啊
Nicholas. Glad I caught you.
尼古拉斯，還好趕上了
Wondered if you wouldn't mind representing us at the am drams tonight.
你們能不能今晚代表大家 出席那個演出
A dateless bargain to engrossing death.
獻給我的愛人
Poison? I'll kiss thy lips.
毒藥？我要親你的嘴唇
Happily some poison doth yet hang on them.
還好上面還殘有點毒藥
Sergeant Angel, hi-hi. Quick word for the Sandford Citizen.
天使警官，你好 給《沙福德公民報》講幾句話吧
It was very enjoyable.
很精彩
- "Cop Enjoys Watching Young Lovers"? - I don't think so.
- 警察喜愛觀看年輕人的愛情故事？ - 我沒這麼說
"Local Bobby Gives Thumbs Up To Teen Suicide"?
本地警察對年輕人的自殺表示讚賞？
That's just grossly inappropriate.
那是非常不合適的
You will try and spell his name correctly this time, won't you, Timothy?
這次你不會寫錯他的名字了吧，小提姆？
Absolute tosh, wasrt it?
真是瞎胡鬧，不是嗎？
And annoyingly, the understudies are actually professional actors.
可惡的是 那些替角才是專業演員
Greg over there was an extra in Straw Dogs
那邊的格雷格曾在《稻草狗》 做臨時演員
and Sheree portrayed a cadaver in Prime Suspect.
謝莉曾在《嫌疑重犯》中演過死屍
Sergeant Angel, you came?
天使警官，你來了啊？
So thrilled you accepted my invitation.
你能接受邀請真是受寵若驚
Well, our Inspector requested we attend. So...
是督察要我們參加的，所以…
Yeah, we can't accept gifts from someone we've officially rebuked so...
是啊，我們不能接受一名 有公務往來的人的禮物，所以…
Jog on.
去死吧
Congratulations to you and to Mrs Blower.
祝賀你和吹牛皮夫人
Oh, this is not my wife. This is Miss Draper. My leading lady.
啊，這不是我妻子 這是德瑞帕小姐，我的女主角
Eve works in the local council, Sergeant. Quite the lady in the know.
伊芙在當地村委會工作，警官 是位通曉內幕的小姐 [導演：伊芙德瑞帕的英文諧音就是「偷聽者」(eavesdropper)]
- I am not. - Nonsense.
- 才不是呢 - 胡說
I'm sure if we bashed your head in, all sorts of secrets would come tumbling out.
我保證如果敲開你的頭 各種各樣的秘密都會跳出來
Romeo, Romeo, a pint of bitter for Romeo?
羅密歐，羅密歐 給羅密歐來一杯苦啤酒？
Thank you very much for coming, George. Excuse us.
歡迎你的到來，喬治，怠慢了
A pleasure, my liege.
很榮幸，陛下
- Eve's nice, ain't she? - She certainly has a distinctive laugh.
- 伊芙很漂亮，是吧？ - 她的笑真是與眾不同
She was in my year at school. Always had a thing for her.
在學校時她跟我同年級 總是有關於她的緋聞
She clearly has a thing for older men.
很顯然她跟那年長的男人有緋聞
What, with Martin Blower? No way!
什麼，跟馬丁·吹牛皮搞？不可能！
We just sat through three hours of so-called acting, Constable,
我們才看了那所謂的 長達三小時的演出，巡警
their kiss was the only convincing moment in it.
演得最投入的就是那吻了
Hey, now you come to mention it,
嘿，既然你提到這點
I too have reason to believe she favours the older gent.
我也有理由相信她對年長的人有偏好
Really? How so?
真的？什麼理由？
Marcus Can'ter's big brother said he'd fingered her up the duck pond.
馬庫斯·坎特的哥哥說 他曾在鴨池旁幫他手淫到高潮
Oh, Officers.
啊，警官
Again let me extend my sincere apologies for earlier.
為我先前的行為 再次致以我最誠摯的歉意
That's quite all right, Mr Blower. Drive safe.
沒什麼的，吹牛皮先生，小心開車
"Drive safe." Oh, my God.
「小心開車」，我的天
You know that's the bloke we done for speeding earlier.
要知道那傢伙才因超速 被我們處理了呢
Yeah. Hopefully, that's the last we'll see of him.
是啊，但願這是我們最後一次見到他
Who is it?
誰啊？
We haven't got long.
快來吧
To us.
今宵漫漫
Who is it?
誰啊?
Yeah?
嗯？
...decaffeinated? - Decaffeinated?
- 脫咖啡因的？
Little Brian Libby found them, out on his paper round.
小布萊恩·利比在送報途中發現他們的
Oh, he'll be having nightmares for a while.
他可要做上一陣子噩夢了
Must have hit the sign at some speed. Took the whole top off.
肯定是以某個速度撞上牌子 把頭都給切掉了
- I've had my top off in this lay-by. - Tits.
- 開這麼靠邊我頭也掉了 - 靠
Most likely lost control, left the road there and then ended up here.
最有可能是失控 從那邊衝出道路然後停在這裡
So, what do we reckon?
那麼，你們說呢？
Sergeant Angel?
天使警官？
Well, we should get a proper cordon off, screen the remains from public view.
我們應該拉上警戒線 別讓公眾看到現場
Close down the road until the ambulance crew arrives,
在救護隊到來之前封閉道路
whereupon we should open a single lane of traffic and ease congestion.
我們可以開條單行道來舒緩交通擁擠
Very good.
非常好
What he said.
照他說的做
- What happened, Danny? - Car accident.
- 發生了什麼事，丹尼？ - 車禍
Nasty way to go.
太糟糕了
Constable, official vocab guidelines state
巡警，官方指南規定
we no longer refer to these incidents as "accidents," they're now "collisions."
我們不再把這類事件稱為「災禍」 而稱之為「衝突」
Right.
明白
"For never was there a story of more woe. Than this of Juliet and her Romeo."
「從來沒有故事能比 羅密歐與朱麗葉更令人哀痛」 （莎士比亞劇台詞）
- Excuse me? - Martin and Eve. Such a tragedy.
- 什麼？ - 馬丁與伊芙，真是場悲劇
Mr Skinner, do you mind telling me
扒皮先生，能否告訴我你怎麼 知道受害人的身份？
You know how it is. News travels fast.
事實就是這樣 好事不出門，壞事傳千里
A love struck Romeo sings a streetsus serenade
愛情撞上了羅密歐 一路哼著小曲
- What happened, Danny? - Traffic collision.
- 發生什麼了，丹尼？ - 交通衝突
Hey, why can't we say "accident" again?
嘿，為什麼不能稱之為事故呢？
Because "accident" implies there's nobody to blame.
因為「事故」暗示著沒人會受到譴責
Put a sock in it, town mouse.
別小題大做了，街鼠
Yeah, you wanna be a big cop in a small town, fuck off up the model village.
你想在這小鎮子做出大成就 他媽的滾出模範村莊
I'm just saying, things aren't always as simple as they look.
我只是說 事情不總是像看上去的那麼簡單
Most times they are.
絕大部分情況是
Let's just wait till Doctor Hatcher comes back with something,
先看看孵化器醫生的化驗結果
before you go jumping the Kalashnikov.
再跳出來射你的衝鋒鎗
All right, in the meantime, why don't you check out a few of Martin Blower's clients?
好吧，與此同時 你們為什麼不查查馬丁·吹牛皮的客戶？
Martin Blower represents damn near most of the village.
馬丁·吹牛皮是村裡大部分人的代理
Did you want us to go through the whole phone book?
你想要我們查遍整個電話簿嗎？
Yeah, or put a call into Aaron A. Aaronson, shall we?
是啊， 先打給艾倫·艾·艾倫的兒子，好嗎？ （電話簿按字母排序A-Z開始）
Please, don't be childish.
請別這麼幼稚
At least consider interviewing the widow.
至少考慮去調查下馬丁妻子
Martin Blower was clearly having an affair with Eve Draper.
馬丁·吹牛皮很明顯跟伊芙·德瑞帕 有風流韻事
Oh, and how did you establish that?
啊，你怎麼這麼確定？
'Cause we sat through three hours of so-called acting last night,
因為我們昨晚看了那所謂的 長達三小時的演出
and the kiss was the only convincing moment in it.
他們演得最真的就是那吻了
All right, pipe down, big one.
好吧，閉嘴，大胖子
Here, what else you got, Crockett and Tubby?
那麼，你還發現了誰的關係？ 克羅基特與黛比？
- Skid marks. - Now who's being childish?
- 剎車痕 - 現在誰在幼稚了？
There were no skid marks at the scene.
車禍現場沒有剎車痕
Doesrt it seem a little strange that Martin Blower would lose control of his car
馬丁·吹牛皮的車失控後也不踩剎車 不覺得有點奇怪嗎？
If there were no skid marks it follows
沒有剎車痕，也就是說300碼內
You don't have to be a detective to work that out!
這麼簡單的道理不用想都知道
Yeah.
就是
- Are you causing trouble? - Yes, they are.
- 你們惹麻煩了嗎？ - 是啊，是他們
Well, a spot of bother up at Ellroy Farm.
艾爾羅伊的農場有了點小狀況
Old Arthur Webley's been clipping hedgerows that don't belong to him.
老亞瑟·溫布利剪掉了不屬他的籬笆
- Yes, sir? - That's it.
- 所以呢，長官？ - 就這樣
Yes, sir.
是的，長官？
- Why do we need the dog? - It's not the dog we need.
- 為什麼要帶條狗？ - 我們需要狗的主人
Right.
好了
What did he say?
他說什麼？
- What did he say? - He said, "An 'edge is an 'edge.
- 他說什麼？ - 他說，不就是條分界線
"He only chopped it down 'cause it spoilt his view.
籬笆擋了他的視線，就砍掉嘍
"What's Reaper moaning about?"
收割機有啥好煩？
Right.
好
Look, I appreciate your position, Mr Webley,
我很同情你的處境，溫布利先生
but you can't go around chopping down other people's hedges without permission.
但你不能在不經允許的情況下 砍倒別人的籬笆
"Yes, I suppose."
嗯，我想是的
Thank you.
謝謝
All right.
好的
Mr Webley, I trust you have a licence for that firearm?
溫布利先生，我想你有持槍證吧？
He does for this one.
他有這支槍的證
What do you mean by "this one"?
有這支的證是什麼意思？
By the power of Grey Skull.
我的老天爺！
Where on earth did you get these?
你從哪兒搞來這些的？
- Found them. - He found them!
- 找到的 - 他找到的！
- And what is this? - Sea mine.
- 這是什麼？ - 水雷
Sea mine.
水雷
Well, Mr Webley, this is an extremely dangerous collection.
溫布利先生 這是件極其危險的收藏品
It's a wonder nobody's been hurt before.
沒人因此受傷真是奇跡
No, it's just a lot of junk.
這只是堆破銅爛鐵
ANGEL: Move, move, move!
跑，跑，快跑！
- TURNER: You what? - No, apparently it's been deactivated. Over.
- 你什麼？ - 不，貌似是枚死雷，完畢
That's right, deactivated!
沒錯，死了！
- It's not live. - It looks live.
- 不是活的 - 看上去還像阿
All right.
好吧
That was quite an impressive haul today, Constable Butterman.
今天真是大獲豐收啊，黃油男巡警
Well, you know, I mean, maybe we should do something to celebrate.
是啊，我說也許該做些什麼慶祝一下
Unless you gotta water your Peace Lily.
除非你要給你的白鶴芋澆水
- What exactly did you have in mind? - I don't know. Pub?
- 你到底打什麼主意？ - 我不知道，去酒館？
MARY: Right you are, my love.
就來，親愛的
Yes, sirs, what can I get you?
你好，先生們，要點什麼？
Pint of lager, please, Roy.
請來一杯啤酒，羅伊
And what can I get you that isn't a cranberry juice?
除了酸果蔓汁你想要什麼？
- I don't really wanna get drunk. - You can get a little drunk.
- 我不想喝醉 - 喝個三分醉就行了
- Okay, I'll have one. - Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
- 好吧，，來一杯 - 嗯，就要這樣嘛
Mr Porter, what's your wine selection?
黑啤先生，你還收藏什麼酒？
Oh, we got red or white.
啊，我們有紅的，還有…
- I'll have a pint of lager, please. - Yeah, Roy.
- 我還是也來一杯啤酒吧 - 好啊，羅伊
- Any news from earlier? - Yeah. CSI found nothing.
- 早先的事情有什麼消息嗎？ - 嗯，CSI什麼都沒發現
Doctor Hatcher reported no misadventure and Mrs Blower has four alibis.
孵化器醫生報告稱沒有謀殺跡象 吹牛皮夫人有四個不在犯罪現場證明
Now, come on, Sergeant, it's not your job to investigate this incident, is it?
拜託，警官 你的職責不包括調查這件事，對吧？
Is it?
對吧？
- No, it isn't.
當然不包括
- You don't switch off, do you? - You sound like my ex.
- 你放不下工作，對吧？ - 你的口氣就像我前女友
- Well, you are always thinking away. - It's what I do.
- 你總是考慮得太多了 - 我就這樣
- Don't get me wrong. I think it's amazing. - Really?
- 別誤解了，我覺得很令人驚歎 - 真的？
I mean, what made you wanna be a policeman?
我說你為什麼想當男警察？
Officer.
是警務人員
What made you wanna be a policeman-officer?
你為什麼想當男警務人員？
I don't remember a time when I didn't wanna be a police officer.
我不記得我什麼時候想當警務人員了
Apart from the summer of 1979 when I wanted to be Kermit the Frog.
1979的夏天之前我的理想是當青蛙克米特 （木偶劇《芝麻街》中的著名角色）
It all started with my Uncle Derek. He was a Sergeant in the Met.
都是受我叔叔德裡克的影響 他在倫敦警察隊做警官
He bought me a police pedal car when I was five.
在5歲時他帶給我輛警用踏板車
I rode round in it every second I was awake.
除了睡覺，我都騎它去抓比我大1倍的孩子
I got beaten up a lot when I was young but it didn't stop me.
我小時候沒少挨揍 但那沒能令我退縮
I wanted to be like Uncle Derek.
我想要成為德裡克叔叔那樣的人
He sounds like a good bloke.
聽起來他是個好人
Actually, he was arrested for selling drugs to students.
實際上，他因向學生兜售毒品而被捕
What a cunt.
真是個龜孫子
Probably bought the pedal car with the proceeds.
也許那輛車也是用贓款買的
Needless to say I never went near it again. I just let it rust.
不用說我再也沒騎過那輛車 把它放一邊生蚺F
But I never forgot the clear sense of right and wrong
但那在踏板車上聲張正義的感覺 我永遠不會忘懷
I had to prove to myself that the law could be proper
我要證明給自己看 法律是公平正義，有益於人類的
It was from that moment, I was destined to be a police officer.
從那刻起，我就立志當一名警務人員
- Shame. - How so?
- 可惜啊 - 為什麼？
I think you would've made a great muppet.
要不你就成為一個偉大的木偶了
What about you? What made you wanna become a police officer?
那你呢？你為什麼想當警務人員？
I don't know. Dad does it.
我不知道 反正我爸是
I think after my mum died, it's what he wanted, you know, keep me close by.
我想自從老媽死後，他只想好好照看我
- Do you mind if I ask how she died? - Traffic collision.
- 介意我問一下她的死因是？ - 交通衝突
I'm sorry.
對不起
Never mind. Hey, watch this.
沒關係 嘿，看好了
- Jesus Christ! - Oh, my eye!
- 我的上帝！ - 啊，我的眼睛！
Hey, come on, silly bollocks, get them in.
拜託，別這麼沉悶了，快喝
- 777. - Mr Skinner.
- 777 - 扒皮先生
- You know George Merchant, don't you? - Evening, Officer.
- 你認識喬治·批發商吧？ - 晚上好，警官
Yes, we were just discussing the accident.
我們剛剛正在談論車禍呢
I'd come to know Martin and Eve very well of late.
我最近才結識了馬丁與伊芙
Such a loss.
就這麼去了
What say we drink to their demise?
為了他們的死喝一杯吧？
Shouldrt that be "drink to their memories"?
應該是為了紀念他們喝一杯吧？
Of course. Cheers.
當然了，乾杯
I must go to the little boys' room.
我要回我的小閨房了
- GEORGE: I'm all right! - "Little" being the operative word.
- 我沒事！ - 他說的不完全對
Oh, he'll be in bits tomorrow.
明天才會變得更「小」
I think somebody needs to go home.
我想有人得回家了
- I'm... I'm not that drunk, sir. - Not you. Him.
- 我還沒那麼醉呢，長官 - 不是你，是他
What?
怎麼了？
Hey, we did get a little drunk. Did you get it?
嘿，我們有點小醉了，你呢？
'Cause he's... He's little and he's drunk.
因為他很小，所以他醉了
Oh, good grief.
啊，天哪！
It's hardly in keeping with the village's rustic aesthetic, is it?
與整個村莊的風格 格格不入，是吧？
- How much do I owe you? - Twenty quid.
- 我欠你多少？ - 20磅
There you go.
拿去
- And there's your change. - God bless you.
- 這是你的找零 - 上帝保佑你
Bye-bye.
再見
I'm all right.
我沒事
I would not wanna be him in the morning.
我明早可不想像他一樣
Well, this is me.
唔，我家到了
Well, I shall see you in the morning.
那明天早上見了
Unless you wanna come in for a cup of coffee?
進來喝一杯咖啡嗎？
- I don't drink coffee. - Tea?
- 我不喝咖啡 - 茶呢？
No caffeine after midday.
我正午後不喝含咖啡因的東西
How about another beer?
啤酒呢？
Oh, dear.
啊，天那
- When did you move in? - About five years ago.
- 你什麼時候搬來的？ - 大概5年前
- You should get some house plants. - Oh, yeah, yeah.
- 你應該搞些室內綠化 - 啊，是啊
Yeah. I've been tending my Peace Lily for about three years now.
我已經照看我的白鶴芋快三年了
It oxygenates the room, helps you think, relieves stress.
它能淨化空氣，有助思考，緩解壓力
Its needs are simple.
需求卻不大
Janine used to say I love my Lily more than I loved her.
珍妮常說我愛花勝過她
- Is that why you split up? - What?
- 那就是你們分手的原因？ - 什麼？
- 'Cause you did it with a plant? - No, no, no.
- 因為你跟植物幹那事？ - 不，不是
It was more about me being obsessed with the job.
更多的是因為我沉迷於工作
That's good though, right?
那樣很好啊，不是嗎？
Is it though?
是嗎？
I did miss a few dinners. You know, parties, a birthday or two.
我錯過了許多晚餐，派對 還有一到兩個生日
- Listen, mate, I... - Her dad's funeral.
- 聽著夥計，我… - 還有他父親的葬禮
- I just wanna be good at what I do. - You are good at what you do.
- 我只是想做好我的本職工作 - 你已經做得很好了
You've just gotta learn to switch off that big old melon of yours.
你只需要關掉你腦袋裡的開關
That's the whole problem, Danny.
那正是問題所在，丹尼
I don't think I know how.
我不知道該怎麼做
I can show you how.
我可以告訴你怎麼辦
By the power of Grey Skull.
我的老天爺！
Point Break or Bad Boys II?
《終極豪情》還是《絕地戰警2》？
Which one do you think I'll prefer?
你覺得我更適合看哪個？
No, I mean which one do you wanna watch first?
不，我是說你想先看哪個？
You are pulling my leg?
你耍我嗎？
What did you think of that?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Well, I won't argue that it was a no holds barred,
我承認這片子很瘋狂，驚險刺激
that amount of carnage and mayhem and not incur a considerable amount of paperwork.
是不可能避免繁重的書面報告
That is nothing, man.
那算什麼，夥計
This is about to go off.
這才叫火爆！
This shit just got real.
這要變成現實了
HATCHER: Nasty way to go.
真是慘啊
I think our Mr Merchant tried to have a little fry up and left the gas on.
我想批發商是想炸點東西吃 但沒關煤氣閥
Spends his whole life devoted to the refrigerator
畢生都獻給了電冰箱 卻被電烤爐給殺了
I told him several times, you shouldn't eat late at night.
我告訴過他多次 深更半夜就不要吃東西了
Oh, I don't know. I quite like a little midnight gobble.
啊，我不知道 我喜歡夜宵
Cocks.
靠
So, what do we reckon? Angel?
那你們怎麼想，天使？
Help me.
幫幫我
Okay, we get a proper cordon up, we let the fire crews finish their stuff,
好的，我們要拉起警戒線 先讓消防隊做完工作
and then we get forensics in to do a thorough sweep of the house.
然後我們找人來對房子進行徹底的清理
Very good. What he said.
非常好，照他說的做
Sergeant Angel, hi-hi. A quick word?
天使警官，你好 講兩句話吧？
Mr Messenger, a statement will be issued shortly.
情報員先生，我們隨後會發表聲明的
Actually, I just wanted to ask, "What's your perfect Sunday?"
實際上，我只是想問 「你完美週日是什麼樣子？
I'll deal with the press, Sergeant.
我來應付媒體吧，警官
Now, my perfect Sunday is a lovely long lie in...
我完美的週日是舒舒服服地躺在…
Fire to destroy all you've done
大火會掩蓋你所做的一切
Like in the films.
就跟電影裡一樣
MAN: Something like, something out of Backdraft.
是有點像，有點像《烈火雄心》
- What are you thinking? Foul play? - ANGEL: Maybe.
- 你怎麼看，謀殺嗎？ - 也許
We're just hoping to talk to the last people to see Mr Merchant alive.
我們想找最後見過批發商 的兩個人談談
Namely a Sergeant Knickerless Asswipe and a Constable Fanny Batterbum.
那就是你可拉屎·擦屁股警官 和胖尼·奶油包巡警
- That's us. - Why is this such a big joke to you?
- 是我們 - 你們覺得很搞笑嗎？
Three people have died in a week.
一周內死了三個人
Oh, come on, Doctor Sherlock, they were accidents.
啊，拜託，福爾摩斯 這都是些意外
People have accidents every day.
意外天天有
- The victims knew each other. - Everyone knows everyone round here.
- 受害者是有關聯的 - 這裡的人都有關聯的
Yeah. If you didn't see anything suspicious, then who did?
是啊，只有你這個沒有關聯的人 才會瞎懷疑
It's a bit of a blind spot, I'm afraid.
恐怕有一點點的盲區
We just catch the very edge of the explosion.
我們只恰好捕捉到了爆炸邊緣
Nasty way to go.
太糟了
- There was something took my eye. - Really? What's that?
- 但有件東西吸引了我 - 真的嗎？是什麼？
Sandford's most wanted.
沙福德的頭號通緝犯
There you go. It was the swan all along.
滿意了吧，是天鵝干的
- This is not funny, Detective! - Oh, give over, Miss Marples.
- 這不好笑，偵探！ - 放棄吧，偵探小姐
Yeah, you do your job and we'll do ours, eh?
你走你的陽關道 我過我的獨木橋
Yeah. Havert you got a church fete to look after?
你不是要參加教堂的活動嗎？
No, I have not!
不，我沒有！
Actually.
實際上有的
Someone's in for a surprise at 3:00, ladies and gentlemen.
將由我們特別推選的嘉賓進行抽獎
Out in the country
鄉間野外
Far from all the sorts of noise of the city
遠離城市的喧囂
There's a village green
有個綠色村莊
It's been a long time since I last set eyes
很久沒有見到過尖頂的教堂
That's me after a couple of pints.
我喝了兩杯酒後就這樣
Splat the rat.
拍老鼠
Shark!
鯊魚！
Seen any murderings, Nicholarse?
看見什麼謀殺了嗎，尼古拉斯？
Come on, boys. Leave Sergeant Angel alone, he's working.
拜託，孩子們 別煩天使警官，他在工作
Sorry, Chief, won't waste any more police time.
對不起，長官 不會再浪費警察的時間了
Have a nice time.
過得愉快
Actually, Nicholas, you might as well take a break.
實際上，尼古拉斯 你也可以休息一下
Hey, great. I've got something to show you.
嘿，太棒了，給你看樣東西
- This is a rifle range. - You'll be really good at it.
- 這是個萊福槍射擊場 - 你一定很在行的
Feeling lucky, Sergeant?
今天手氣好嗎，警官？
Three cans wins you the squeaky bunny, five cans gets you the floppy lion.
射中三個罐子得吱吱兔 五個得邋遢獅
Take out all the little people, you get to waltz off with the cuddly monkey.
射倒所有的小人 你就可以跟抱抱猴跳華爾茲了
I thought I made it clear to you how I feel about firearms.
我還以為你明白我對火槍的看法的
It's only an air rifle.
只是空氣槍而已
Sergeant.
警官
Dear Lord!
我的天！
That was amazing.
神槍手啊
- Thank you, Danny. - I can't believe I shot someone.
- 謝謝你，丹尼 - 真不敢相信我射中人了
- He's a doctor, he can deal with it. - I never shot anyone before.
- 他是名醫生，他能應付得來了 - 我以前從未射過人
Danny, believe me, it's not something you ever get used to.
丹尼，相信我 你適應不了那種感覺的
Yeah. Maybe we should go on the bouncy castle.
是啊，也許我們該去蹦蹦堡
Take our minds off of it.
放鬆下心情
- Sergeant Angel, hi-hi. - Mr Messenger.
- 天使警官，嗨嗨！ - 情報員先生
I need to talk to you about George Merchant. Alone.
我要單獨跟你談談喬治·批發商
Churchyard. 3:00.
在墓地，3點鐘
What do you think he wants?
你覺得他想幹什麼
REVEREND SHOO TER: Would Sergeant Angel come to the stage, please?
請天使警官到台上來，好嗎？
Here to announce the winners is the newest addition to the Sandford Police Force.
宣佈獲獎者的是最新加入 沙福德治安機關的…
Service.
是部門
Sergeant Nicholas Angel.
尼古拉斯·天使警官
- Prick. - Wanker.
- 雞巴 - 手淫豬
Hello. Hello.
喂，喂
The first name is Simon Skinner.
第一位是西蒙·扒皮
He's in the loo.
他在洗手間
Too much of Joyce's lemonade, perhaps.
也許是喝了太多喬伊絲的檸檬水
And the next name is...
下一個是…
Tim, your number's up.
提姆，輪到你了
Excuse me. Excuse me.
借過，借過
Hi-hi.
嗨嗨
Oh, no!
啊，不！
Stand back, stand back! There's been a terrible accident.
靠後，靠後 發生了一件意外
- Accident? - Just an accident.
- 意外？ - 只是起事故而已
It's all right, it's all right. There's nothing to see.
沒事了，沒事了 沒什麼好看的.
Come on, everybody. It's all right. It's just an accident.
拜託大夥兒，沒事了 只是起事故而已
FRANK: Nicholas, what is it?
尼古拉斯，怎麼了？
Sir, I think all these deaths are linked. I think Tim Messenger was murdered.
長官，我覺得這些死亡都是有聯繫的 我認為提姆·情報員死於謀殺
- Who could do something like this? - Maybe it was the swan.
- 誰會這麼做呢？ - 也許是天鵝
- Apparently, they can break a mars arm. - Or blow up a mars house.
- 很明顯，它們能打斷人的肩膀 - 或者是炸掉房子
- Listen, you pair of... - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, Nicholas.
- 聽著，你們這對… - 停，停，尼古拉斯
Now, let me get this straight.
讓我直截了當吧
- Are you saying that this is a crime scene? - Yes, sir, I am.
- 你說這是犯罪現場？ - 是的，長官
Very well.
非常好
- Detectives. - Sir.
- 偵探們 - 長官
Start interviewing everyone who was at the fete.
開始調查參與活動的所有人
Oh, he's got shorts on.
啊，他喝醉了
- Sergeant Fisher? - What?
- 漁夫警官？ - 怎麼了？
- Secure the area.
- 保護現場 - 什麼？
- PC Thatcher? - Yes, love?
- 茅屋匠警員？ - 是的，親愛的？
Get the CSI down here.
叫CSI過來
PC Walker?
步行者警員？
Patrol the churchyard with Saxon.
帶撒克遜巡邏墓地
Nicholas, Danny, you know what to do.
尼古拉斯，丹尼 你們知道該怎麼辦
Do you really think this is murder?
你真的認為這是起謀殺？
I just don't think we should rule it out, that's all.
我只是覺得有這個可能
Yeah. I think you're right.
嗯，我想你是對的
I think you're talking a load of old shit.
我覺得你是在放屁
He thinks you're talking a load of shit. Swings and roundabouts, isn't it?
他覺得你在放屁 有進必有出嘛，對不對？
CARTWRIGHT: Pain in the arse.
討厭鬼
- Did you find anything? - Yeah.
- 找到什麼了嗎？ - 是啊
I was extremely shocked when I looked at my watch
我看了手錶後 很吃驚自己怎麼沒在就酒館裡
Did you go to his house? Did you read his articles?
你去過他的家嗎？ 你讀過他的文章嗎？
If you wanna wade through every copy of the Sandford bloody Citizen, be our guest.
如果要讀遍每份該死的 《沙福德公民報》，你自己干
It's your job, isn't it? Detect!
這不是你們的工作嗎？做調查！
This ain't the city, Mr Angel. Not everyone's a murdering psychopath.
這不是在市裡，天使先生 並不是所有人都有謀殺精神病傾向
It's high time you realised that. You and your monkey.
你和你的猴子現在該意識到了
Did he mean me or that?
他是指我還是它？
Oh, maybe we should go home.
也許我們該回家
- What do you mean? - Well, there's nothing going on, is there?
- 你什麼意思？ - 這裡又沒什麼活幹？
Have you listened to anything that I've said?
你到底有沒有聽進我說的話？
What do you mean?
你指什麼？
Is anything I've told you in the last two weeks
你的笨腦子有沒有記住一點…
- sunk into that thick skull of yours? - Yeah.
- 我上兩周說的話？ - 有啊
Has it? Like what?
是嗎？比如？
You said I could be an amazing policeman-officer.
你說我能成為一名出色的警務人員
There's always something going on, Danny.
隨時都會發生狀況，丹尼
And you won't be an amazing police officer until you understand that.
除非你明白這點 你就成不了一名出色的警務人員
Well, I remembered something else you said and all.
我記住了你所說的一些其他話
- Oh, did you now? - Yeah.
- 啊，是嗎？ - 嗯
You don't know how to switch off!
你不知道該如何放下工作！
Well, if you wanna wade through every copy
如果想讀遍每份該死的 《沙福德公民報》，自己幹吧
- Morning, Constable. - All right?
- 早上好，巡警 - 怎麼？
Thanks for the monkey.
謝謝你把猴子送給我
- Yours, isn't it? - I won it for you.
- 本來就是你的 - 我是為你贏的
Danny, I think I'm on to something.
胖子，我覺得我有些頭緒了
- Are you? - Yes.
- 是嗎？ - 是的
And I think with a little deliberation we can figure out what links these deaths.
我認為只要稍加思索 我們就能找出這些死亡間的聯繫
- We? - Come on, partner. Let's go to work.
- 我們？ - 快來，搭檔，有活幹了
Oh, oh, Sergeant Angel?
啊，天使警官？
- Someone from London called for you. - Tell them I'll call them back.
- 倫敦有人打電話找你 - 告訴他們我會回復的
- Tim Messenger. - Go.
- 提姆·情報員 - 開始
Editor and journalist at The Sandford Citizen.
《沙福德公民報》的記者及主編
- Fondness for puns. - Go on.
- 愛說雙關語 - 繼續
- Terrible speller. - Oh, yeah?
- 老是拼錯 - 哦，是嗎？
Nevertheless had uncovered important information about...
但他曾經報道過…
- George Merchant. - Self-made millionaire.
- 喬治·批發商 - 一位白手起家的百萬富翁
Fancied himself as a property developer.
覺得自己是個地產投資商
- Said he had big plans for Sandford. - Pissed on the floor in The Crown.
- 說他在沙福德裡有個大計劃 - 在皇冠酒館裡隨地尿尿
But more importantly, was a good friend and client of...
但更重要的是 他還是誰的顧客和朋友？
- Martin Blower. - Respected solicitor.
- 馬丁·吹牛皮 - 令人尊敬的律師
- Affirmatron. - Leading light of the local drama society.
- 是的 - 當地歌舞劇社團的重要人物
- Bad actor. - Undoubtedly.
- 演技很爛 - 沒錯
- Bad driver. - Not necessarily.
- 駕駛技術不怎麼樣 - 難說
- Cheated on his missus. - Most certainly.
- 搞婚外戀 - 很顯然
- And we both know who with. - Eve Draper.
- 我們知道他情婦是誰 - 伊芙·德瑞帕
- Blower's leading lady. Distinctive laugh. - True.
- 吹牛皮的女主角，笑得夠誇張 - 是啊
- Favoured older men. - Fingered.
- 喜歡上年紀的人 - 手淫
- Worked at? - Council.
- 在哪兒上班？ - 村委會
- More specifically? - Department of Planning and Development.
- 再具體點 - 計劃發展部
Where George Merchant secured permission
喬治·批發商就在那兒 得到在諾裡斯大道造那奇怪公寓的許可
So...
所以呢？
Maybe they were all accidents. People have accidents every day.
或許那些真的是意外
- What are you two up to? - Nothing.
- 你們倆在做什麼？ - 沒什麼
Well, look sharp.
哦，那快看啊
- There's been reports of a fire in the station. - What?
- 局裡起火了 - 什麼？
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
- Danny, why didn't you say something? - We were working, werert we?
- 胖子，你為什麼不吭一聲 - 我們不在忙嘛
- Hey, where are you going? - Personal errand.
- 嘿，你去那兒？ - 一點私事
Hello, Miss Tiller.
你好啊，耕種機女士
I was wondering, do you have any Japanese Peace Lilies?
你這裡有賣白鶴芋花嗎？
Of course.
有，有
I was just about to pop off, actually.
我剛準備打烊
I can never find my scissors.
我總找不到剪刀
- Is this for someone special? - Yes. Yes, it is.
- 是要送給特別的人？ - 是，是的
- Are you going somewhere, Miss Tiller? - Yes. I'm moving away.
- 你要離開一陣嗎，耕種機女士 - 是的，我要搬走了
And why the move, if you don't mind me asking?
不介意我問一下您為什麼要搬走嗎？
- Well, just between you and I... - Yes?
- 那我只對你一個人說… - 嗯？
- You know that fella who blew up? - George Merchant.
- 你知道那被炸飛的… - 喬治·批發商
Well, George Merchant, God rest him, wanted to buy this land,
那個喬治·批發商，阿彌陀佛， 想要買這塊地皮
so he sends round his legal fella, Martin Blower, God rest him,
他送來律師，馬丁·吹牛皮 阿彌陀佛
and I thought I might take them up on it.
我那時就同意了
I haven't really got that much family round here, save for Cousin Sissy.
除了娘娘腔表哥， 我在這裡沒什麼親戚
So I thought I might take them up on the offer and move to Buford Abbey.
所以我就簽了合同，搬去布福德·艾比
Would you like a card with this?
要張祝賀卡片嗎？
No, sorry, you were talking about the offer?
不，抱歉 你剛說那合同？
Well, it turns out that Martin Blower, God rest him,
那個，原來那馬丁·吹牛皮， 阿彌陀佛
knew where the new bypass road is going
他知道這裡要開一條新路
because he was knocking off Eve Draper from the council, God rest her,
因為他想把伊芙·德瑞帕踢出村委會 阿彌陀佛
and then that reporter, God rest him, finds out about the route
還有那記者，阿彌陀佛 發現了這開道計劃
and tells me this land's very valuable.
他告訴我這塊地很值錢
Ten times what George Merchant and Martin Blower, God rest them, offered me.
比喬治和馬丁給的價要高10倍 阿彌陀佛
So, with them having passed on, I decided to sell it on myself
既然他們都過世了 我就決定自己來…
to some folks from the city that Martin, George and Eve,
賣給馬丁, 喬治和伊芙他們…
God rest the lot of them, had been talking to.
提起過的另一些生意人 阿彌陀佛
Apparently, they want to build a big shopping centre or something.
好像他們想造一個超級購物中心什麼的
Of course, Cousin Sissy won't be too happy about that,
當然娘娘腔表哥不會願意
but as far as I'm concerned, Cousin Sissy can go and fuck...
但我覺得娘娘腔表哥可以去操…
Would you just excuse me, for just one second?
你能不能等我一下
Stop!
站住！
In the name of the law!
我以法律的名義命令你！
Hang about, hang about.
慢著...慢著...
You're saying this wasrt an accident?
你說這不是意外？
Leslie Tiller was fucking murdered!
萊絲莉·耕種機是操他媽被謀殺的！
- What, just like Tim Messenger? - Yes!
- 怎麼，和提姆 情報員一樣？ - 是的！
- And George Merchant?
- 還有喬治 批發商?
- And Eve Draper? - Yes!
- 伊芙·德瑞帕？ - 是的！
- And Martin Blower? - No, actually.
- 那馬丁·吹牛皮？ - 那倒不是
- Really? - 'Course he fucking was!
- 真的？ - 操他媽的是！
Thank you, Danny.
謝了，胖子
Oh, murder, murder, murder. Change the fucking record.
哦，謀殺，謀殺，謀殺 還要他媽的修改記錄了
Thank you, Andy.
謝了，安迪
Come on, Sergeant, you've gotta accept it was just another nasty accident.
拜託，警官 你必須面對現實，這只是件意外
What are you suggesting?
那你是什麼意思？
That Leslie Tiller tripped and fell on her own shears?
萊絲莉·耕種機跌倒在自己的剪刀上？
Ben Fletcher fell on his pitchfork the other week.
本·弗萊徹前幾周跌倒在草耙上
Yeah, accidents happen all the time. What makes you think it was murder?
就是，有意外是很正常的 你憑什麼覺得這是謀殺？
- Because I was there! - There's a point.
- 因為我就在現場！ - 那你說說…
Why were you there?
你當時在哪兒做什麼？
I was buying Constable Butterman a Japanese Peace Lily for his birthday.
我在買黃油男警員的生日禮物
What absolute horseshit.
說什麼鬼話
I chased a suspect from the scene. Innocent people don't run!
我追過逃離現場的疑犯 無辜的人為什麼要逃跑！
Here, maybe it was our old friend, the cactus thief.
或許是個慣犯，專偷仙人掌
Oh, yeah, he was a prickly customer, werert he?
那他身上的刺還有夠多的
Am I going completely mad?
難道是我瘋了嗎？
Maybe you are.
或許…是瘋了
Maybe you did it.
或許…是你幹的
Yeah, seeing as how you're such a big fan of murder.
就是，你總把謀殺掛嘴上
- What the... - Sergeant Angel?
- 我操你… - 天使警官
Yes! Sir.
什麼？！長官
Nicholas, Nicholas, Nicholas.
尼古拉斯，尼古拉斯，尼古拉斯
What am I going to do with you?
我該拿你怎麼辦
- Sir, you have to understand... - No, you have to understand.
- 長官，你必須知道… - 不，你必須明白
The boys here aren't used to the concepts you're bandying about.
一時間，隊員們是無法接受你的推斷
The "M" word, Nicholas.
「謀殺」這個推斷，尼古拉斯
There hasn't been a recorded murder in Sandford for 20 years.
沙福德村已經有20年沒有謀殺記錄了
But, sir, I'm certain.
但，長官，這我能肯定
And what's more, I know who did it.
而且我還知道是誰幹的
Can I see the manager, please?
請叫你們經理來
Mr Skinner to the Manager's office. Manager's office. Mr Skinner.
請扒皮先生到經理室 經理室，扒皮先生
Sergeant Angel. And to what do I owe this pleasure?
天使警官，有失遠迎啊
Simon Skinner, I'm arresting you on suspicion of the murder of Leslie Tiller.
西蒙·扒皮 我以你謀殺萊絲莉·耕種機的嫌疑逮捕你
Leslie Tiller's dead? How?
萊絲莉·耕種機死了？怎麼死的？
She tripped and fell on her own shears.
她跌倒在自己的剪子上了
I'm also arresting you on suspicion of the murder of Tim Messenger on May 1st,
我還要以你在5月1日 謀殺提姆·情報員…
of George Merchant on April 29th
4月29日謀殺喬治·批發商…
and of Eve Draper and Martin Blower on April 28th.
和4月28日謀殺伊芙·德瑞帕 和馬丁·吹牛皮的嫌疑逮捕你
- Why on earth would I do that, Sergeant? - I'm glad you asked.
- 那我殺他們的動機是什麼，警官？ - 問得好
My suspicions were first aroused when you appeared
我那次看到你這位只會在鎮中心出現的人 駕車出現在村郊外，就起了疑心
I couldn't help but recall your comments at the theatre on the previous evening.
我還記得你在歌劇結束後的發表的評論
When you not only indicated an awareness of the couple's affair
你不僅表露你知道他們的姦情
but also inferred that Eve's connections at the council
還指出伊芙和村委會的關係…
might make her privy to important information.
可讓她獲取重要情報
You even spoke of "bashing her head in."
你甚至還說要「砍」她的腦袋
Perhaps hoping you might discover the route of the proposed Sandford Bypass.
希望能打探到沙福德開道計劃的內幕
You were already suspicious that George Merchant was buying up
你已經注意到喬治·批發商看了提姆·情報員 在《沙福德公民報》上的文章後
after an article Tim Messenger wrote in the Sandford Citizen.
開始大量收買沙福德郊外的地皮
You see, the land Merchant was buying had little value in of itself but,
你知道批發商買的地皮不值幾個銅板
if it became accessible by road, it would be a prime location for say,
但如果旁邊開條公路的話， 就會變成…怎麼說…
a retail park.
一個購物中心
Consumed with concern for your business
你因為擔心客人們的流失
and potential disloyalty from fickle customers,
會讓生意慘淡
you yourself expressed a wish to behead.
你就想先下手為強
You killed the competition in cold blood.
無情的殺害競爭對手
Staging the murders as accidents.
還製造意外的假象
You used a vehicle removal truck to stage the Blower-Draper death
你用拖車做了吹牛皮—德瑞帕死亡的第二現場
and incinerated an old man in his own house.
還製造鹹肉和豌豆烹飪失誤的假象 連人帶屋燒了個精光
However, there was a loose end.
不過，百密必有一疏
Tim Messenger.
那下午，提姆·情報員被砸死前 告訴了萊絲莉·耕種機…
Upon discovering she was about to sell up to the developers,
在知道耕種機要自己賣地皮後
you brutally murdered her with her own shears.
你就殘忍的用剪刀刺殺她
And made good your escape utilising your impressive skills as a fun runner.
利用你業餘賽跑員的速度 迅速逃離現場
Very entertaining. But I rather think you've been watching too many films.
很精彩 不過你是不是電影看多了？
He hasn't.
他真的沒有
Why would I kill Leslie? You clearly aren't aware that we're related.
那我為什麼要殺萊絲莉？ 很明顯你還不知道我和她是親戚
Oh, but I am, "Cousin Sissy."
但是，我知道你就是「娘娘腔表哥」
I'm afraid my nickname of Sissy is only a revelation to yourself.
可我這個「娘娘腔」綽號是你自己編造
My teenage years studying ballet are well known.
我年輕時跳過芭蕾，這眾所周知
- Yeah, Sissy Skinner. - What a Gaylord.
-  是啊，娘娘腔扒皮 - 同性戀上帝
Thank you, Andrews.
謝謝，安德魯
Now, despite my comments about "beheading" customers,
儘管我說過我要「砍」我的顧客
I personally relish the competition of another store.
我個人比較喜歡同行競爭
Anything to energise my workforce.
這樣可以激勵我的工人
And anyway, what makes you think I could dislodge part of the church roof?
再說，我怎麼可能鏟一塊教堂屋頂的碎片…
Or for that matter, stage a car crash?
亦或者，製造車禍假象？
It's a well known fact that the church roof is in dire need of repair.
誰都知道，教堂的屋頂需要翻修
And isn't it true that two of your own employees
而且你的兩名員工不也為村委會 做拖車工作？
Sergeant, this is the 21st Century.
警官，現在已經是21世紀了
Many people hold down several jobs.
做多份兼職又不奇怪
I myself host a life drawing class at the Village Hall.
我還在村委大廳裡教繪畫課
Tina here is a table dancer at Flappers.
提娜也是「雛女吧」的舞女
Nevertheless, you could have utilised the vehicle removal truck for your own ends.
隨你怎麼說 你還是能用拖車達到你的目的
These accusations are quite meaningless, Sergeant,
你這些指控是站不住腳的，警官
unless you can back them up with hard evidence.
再拿出些更有力的證據吧
Well, you've got me there.
你說的沒錯
I'd need something conclusive.
我的確需要確鑿的證據 證明你的在場證據
Perhaps a wound you sustained on a piece of broken glass this very evening.
或許就是今晚你傷口上的留下的玻璃碎片
This very evening.
玻璃碎片
Sergeant, this is beginning to get embarrassing.
警官，現在你要怎麼解釋
How could I possibly be in several places at once?
我怎麼可能 在同時出現在不同的地方？
I'm sure the store's security footage will absolve me.
超市的監控錄像可以證明我的清白
Do feel free to spool through.
你想看多久就看多久
I can handle this, Danny.
我一個人就行了，胖子
You might as well go back and just enjoy the rest of your birthday.
你該回去繼續慶祝你的生日
- Did you really get me that plant? - Yes, I did.
- 你真的給我買了那盆花？ - 是啊，買了
But it's been impounded as evidence.
不過…現在被當成證物扣押了
Well, I mean, maybe Dad will still let me water it, eh?
那麼，嗯.. 老爸會不會同意我去澆澆水？
Yeah.
嗯
Sergeant, I wanted you to know that
警官，我跟你說…
if I do indeed now own the land belonging to...
如果我真的得到屬於…
belonging to Leslie, that I intend to turn it into a memorial garden, in her honour.
屬於萊絲莉的土地 我會以她的名義造一座公園悼念她
Mr Skinner, what you do with your land is of no concern of mine,
扒皮先生 你要怎麼使用土地和我無關，所以…
So jog on.
去死吧
Michael, will you escort the Sergeant off the premises when he's quite finished?
邁克，等警官忙完後 能陪他回他的住處嗎？
Yarp.
好的
I just can't believe Leslie's dead. How did it happen?
真不敢相信萊絲莉死了 怎麼死的？
She tripped and fell on her own shears.
她跌倒在剪刀上了
Hey, that werert me.
嘿，不是我幹的
Hey, look.
看呀！
Look, Mr Treacher's got his big coat on again.
叛徒先生又穿上他的風衣了
- You want anything from the shop? - Cornetto.
- 去店裡買點吃的？ - 可愛多
- No luck catching them killers, then? - It's just the one killer, actually.
-還沒抓到那些殺人犯？ - 其實就一個殺人犯
- What's the matter? You got brain-freeze? - No, I got brainwave.
- 怎麼了？凍著腦袋了？ - 不，我想到了
Get us back to the station, now!
我們立即回警局！
- It's more than one person. - Come again?
- 不止一個人 - 又來了？
- It's more than one killer. - It was Skinner a minute ago.
- 不止一個殺人犯 - 剛不是說是扒皮干的？
Yeah, well, maybe it still is.
是，不過，或許是的
You know, maybe he's... Maybe he's not alone. Maybe there are others.
其實，或許他…或許他不是單干的 或許還有其他人
Nicholas, you're an exceptional officer. But I've seen this before.
尼古拉斯，你是位出色的警官 我以前也遇到過
- Sir? - Sergeant Popwell.
- 長官？ - 冒泡警官
It was exactly the same thing.
就和現在一樣
You've come from a city where there's danger round every corner,
你們以前工作的地方危機四伏
and it's driven you round the bend.
導致你太過敏感
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
Do yourself a favour. Sleep on it.
為你自己考慮一下 去睡一覺
And if you still feel the same in the morning, I give you my word, I'll get right on to it.
如果明早你沒改變想法的話 我保證我會妥善處理的
Hey. Hey, what's happening? What's going on?
嗨，怎麼了？ 怎麼樣了？
Nothing, nothing. I'm just gonna go back to the hotel.
沒什麼 我要回旅館了
- I mean, do you want a lift? - No, no, I could do with a walk.
- 那你要搭我的車嗎？ - 不，我可以步行
Hey, big one, playtime's over.
大個子，遊戲結束了
SKINNER ON WALKIE-TALKIE: Michael?
邁克？
Michael? Are you there?
你在嗎？
Michael? Is everything okay?
邁克，事情辦得怎麼樣？？
Yarp.
好的
Sergeant Angel's been taken care of?
解決掉天使警官了？
He's not gonna get back up again?
他不會再找麻煩了？
Narp!
壞的
Good. Proceed to the castle.
很好，現去城堡那裡
Frank, this shit just got real.
弗蘭克，事情鬧大了
Skinner just sent someone to kill me, and, now, now he's gone somewhere.
扒皮真的找人想幹掉我 現在，現在他要去…
Up to the... To the castle, I think. I'm gonna... I'm gonna go after him.
好像要去…城堡那裡 我得…我得跟上他
Okay? It's Nicholas, by the way.
就這樣，我是尼古拉斯
Oh, my God. What happened to your Peace Lily?
哦，天哪
Danny. Danny, just stay here, okay? And watch him, and call your dad.
胖子，胖子，在這裡等著好嗎？ 看著他，給你爸打電話
- Tell him I was right. - What are you gonna do?
- 告訴他我得推斷是正確的 - 你要幹什麼？
- I'm gonna bust this thing wide open. - Nicholas, wait.
- 我要去揭發他們 - 尼古拉斯，等等
- You might need this. - Thanks, partner.
- 這能派上用場 - 謝了，搭檔
SKINNER: How could I possibly be in several places at once?
我怎麼可能 在同時出現在不同的地方？
JO YCE: I just can't believe Leslie's dead. How did it happen?
真不敢相信萊絲莉死了 怎麼死的？
WEAVER: You'll find that we run a very tight ship here.
你會發現我們很有組織性的
REVEREND SHOO TER: Who could do something like this?
誰會這麼做呢？
HATCHER: Seems like Mr Merchant tried to have a little fry up and left the gas on.
我想批發商是想炸點東西吃 但沒關煤氣閥
HATCHER: Nasty way to go.
太糟了
AMANDA: What happened, Danny?
發生了什麼事，丹尼？
ANNETTE: No luck catching them killers, then?
還沒抓到那些殺人犯?
No luck catching them...
還沒抓到…
Now, quick announcement before we begin.
現在是會前公告
Janet Barker has decided to call her boys Roger and Martin.
珍妮特·剝皮機決定給孩子們 取名為羅傑和馬丁
And the christening will be a week on Saturday and we're all invited.
下週六便是洗禮儀式 我們都被邀請出席
- Tom. - Thanks, Joyce.
- 湯姆 - 謝謝，喬伊絲
Now, you'll all be delighted to hear
現在有個好消息
that the tenacious Sergeant Angel has been taken care of.
那頑固的天使警官已經上西天了
Joyce will discover the Sergeant lying on the wet floor of his bathroom,
喬伊絲明天會發現他在洗手間裡滑倒 扭斷了脖子
So, with the dispatch of the Sergeant,
那處理了那警官後…
we will now be able to concentrate on the eradication of our hoodie infestation.
我們可以專心根除那群帽子黨
Quite right.
沒錯
After which, nothing will stand in our way.
在那之後，我們便高枕無憂了
Oh, I beg to differ, Mr Weaver.
你錯了，織布工先生
Well, well, well, I see we have visitors.
哎呀呀，我們有客人了
Sergeant Nicholas Angel. Sandford Police Service.
我是尼古拉斯·天使警官 紗福德的警務人員
My, he is tenacious, isn't he?
老天，他是夠頑固的
I'm arresting you under suspicion of conspiracy to commit murder.
我要以故意謀殺的嫌疑逮捕你們
Oh, come, come, Sergeant.
不要激動，警官
You should be ashamed.
你們真可恥
- Calling yourself a community that cares. - Oh, but we do care, Nicholas.
- 妄稱自己在乎社區 - 可我們真的在乎，尼古拉斯
It's all about the greater good.
這都是為了村莊好
ALL: The greater good.
為村莊好
How can this be for the greater good?
這怎麼可能是為了村莊好？
You see, as much as I enjoyed your wild theories, Sergeant,
其實，我很欣賞你的那些推斷，警官
the truth is far less complex.
但事實卻要簡單得多
Blower's fate was simply the result of his being an appalling actor.
吹牛皮的死是因為他拙劣的演技
ALL: Quite appalling.
演得不好
You murdered him for that?
你們就為這個殺了他？
- Well, he murdered Bill Shakespeare. - What?
- 他侮辱了莎士比亞 - 什麼？
The Dramatic Society is an important feather in our cap.
擁有一個歌舞劇社團 能幫助贏得競賽
HATCHER: Couldrt let Blower jeopardise that.
不能讓吹牛皮壞了好事
Not when we had two semi-professionals waiting in the wings.
竟讓兩個比較專業的演員 等在後台
Let's not forget that Greg was an extra in Straw Dogs.
別忘了格雷格曾是《稻草狗》的臨時演員 （《稻草狗》於1971年上映）
And Sheree played a cadaver in Prime Suspect.
還有謝莉在《嫌疑重犯》裡扮演過死屍
Yes, I know!
這我知道！
Martin was less concerned with the reputation of the village
馬丁根本不在乎小鎮的聲譽
than he was with his sordid affair with Eve Draper.
更在乎他和伊芙·德瑞帕那噁心的姦情
And so Eve deserved to die too?
所以伊芙也該死？
Well, she did have a very annoying laugh.
反正她笑起來很難聽
ALL: Annoying.
難聽
- And, and George Merchant? - He had an awful house.
- 那麼喬治·批發商呢？ - 他的房子不好看
ALL: Awful.
不好看
We begged him in vain to make his residence
我們勸他改建成鄉村格調
more in keeping with the village's rustic aesthetic.
融入社區，但他不肯
And what about Tim Messenger? What was his crime?
那，那·提姆 情報員呢？ 他哪兒不對了？
Tim Messenger's tenure as editor of the Sandford Citizen has been unbearable.
我們受不了提姆·情報員 做《沙福德公民報》編輯
Our once great paper had become riddled with tabloid journalism.
在有名的報刊上發表無聊的文章
Not to mention persistent errors.
更別提他別字連篇
- He listed her age as 55. - When, actually, I'm 53.
- 還把她寫成55歲 - 其實我才53歲
Fifty-three.
53歲
What, what about Leslie Tiller? One of your own?
那萊絲莉·耕種機呢？ 聯盟的人也殺？
Her horticultural expertise helped put Sandford on the map.
她的園藝技術使沙福德聞名遐邇
Oh, she was ever so good.
她真的太能幹了
Cousin Leslie was a terrible shame.
但萊絲莉表妹也是我們的恥辱
But it seemed she was set on moving away.
她竟然決定要搬走
We couldn't have her sharing her green fingers with anybody else.
我們決不能讓別人得到她的技能
Not least those heathens at Buford Abbey.
特別是不信耶穌的布福德·艾比
If we can't have her, no one can.
我們得不到的 別人也休想得到
How can this be for the greater good?
這些不可能讓村莊更好
- ALL: The greater good. - Shut it!
- 為村莊好 - 夠了！
These people died for no reason. No reason whatsoever!
這些人死得莫名 簡直是莫名其妙！
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
哦，我可不同意
Hello, Nicholas.
你好，尼古拉斯
I was like you once.
我以前也和你一樣
I believed in the immutable word of the law.
在我失去了我愛人前
That is until the night Mrs Butterman was taken from me.
我也相信法律是公正的
You see, no one loved Sandford more than her.
沒人比她更愛沙福德
She was head of the Womers Institute, chair of the floral committee.
她曾是婦女協會和花卉協會的主席
When they started the Village of the Year contest,
直到年度最佳村莊競賽開始
she worked round the clock. I've never seen such dedication.
她晝夜不停的工作 敬業到我無法想像的地步
On the eve of the adjudicator's arrival, some travellers moved into Callahan Park.
在評委抵達的那晚 幾個遊客闖進卡拉翰公園
Before you could say, "Gypsy scum," we were knee-deep in dog muck,
在能喊出「吉卜賽人渣」前 我們已經在沒及膝蓋的狗屎裡了
thieving kids and crusty jugglers.
他們全是些偷雞摸狗的孩子 和厚臉皮的騙子
ALL: Crusty jugglers.
厚臉皮騙子
We lost the title and Irene lost her mind.
我們輸了比賽，艾琳就瘋了
She drove her Datsun Cherry into Sandford Gorge.
她駕車衝出了沙福德峽谷
From that moment on, I swore that I would do her proud.
從那時起，我發誓我會讓她驕傲
And whatever the cost, we would make Sandford great again.
不惜任何代價，我們會使沙福德變得更美好
Sir, this doesn't make any sense.
長官，我還是不明白
The adjudicators arrive tomorrow. We had to get everything ready.
評委們明天就要到了 我們必須作足準備
Are you saying this is all about winning the Best Village Award?
這些都是為了贏得最佳村莊獎？
This is the best village, Nicholas. You've seen the people.
這裡就是最好的小村，尼古拉斯 你也見到了
- They're happy, contented. - They're living in a dream world.
- 鎮民們很幸福，很滿足 - 他們住的是桃花源
Sergeant Popwell thought much the same as you.
冒泡警官當初也和你想的一樣
I'm disappointed you can't see the bigger picture.
沒想到你竟是只井底之蛙
Well, I'm happy to disappoint you, sir.
抱歉讓你失望了，長官
And I'm afraid you're gonna have to come with me.
但我還是要您和我去一次警署
You are all gonna have to come with me.
你們所有人都必須跟我走
No, Nicholas, I'm afraid it is you
不，尼古拉斯 我想是你…
who is going to have to come with us.
必須跟我們走一趟
Danny, no.
胖子，住手
Back off! Back off!
退下！退下！
Or I swear to God, you'll be explaining how Danny tripped over
不然你們就要想像 丹尼是如何跌倒，掉了腦袋
Come on, Nicholas. You haven't got it in you.
少來了，尼古拉斯 你沒這個膽
I mean it!
我認真的！
Shit!
我操！
FRANK: (ECHOING) Gypsy scum. Travellers.
吉卜賽人渣 旅客
Thieving kids. Dog muck.
偷雞摸狗的孩子 狗屎
Crusty jugglers.
厚臉皮騙子
There hasn't been a recorded murder in Sandford for 20 years.
沙福德村已經有20年沒有謀殺記錄了
There's a reason we accommodate a few of the younglings at the pub.
我們允許一些年輕人進酒吧是有原因的
Spot of bother up at Ellroy Farm.
艾爾羅伊的農場有了點小狀況
I'll make sure everyone gets their just deserts.
我一定會給大家個滿意的交代
(VOICES ECHOING)
一臉大鬍子
WEAVER: If we don't come down hard on these clowns...
如果我們不對這些小丑 採取些嚴厲措施的話
FRANK: We'll get round to it.
我們會立馬處理的
Danny!
胖子！
- (WHISPERING) What are you doing? - Saving your skin.
- 你在幹什麼？ - 救你呢
- This is murder! - It's not, it's ketchup.
- 簡直就是謀殺！ - 其實是綁架啦
I'm not talking about that, I'm talking about the others.
我不是指這個 我是說那群人
- What others? - The others the NWA have murdered.
- 哪群人？ - 被NWA幹掉的那群人
- That's not true. - It is!
- 不可能 - 是真的！
Dad just said it was his special club, he...
老爸說這是一個特殊俱樂部
I thought it was about rapping people on the knuckles
我以為是為眾人主持公道的
- and sending them on their way. - There are skeletons back there!
- 幫他們走上正軌 - 那裡堆得全是骷髏！
I don't know nothing about no skelingtons.
我怎麼不知道什麼骷髏
- What did you think was happening? - Not this!
- 你以為是什麼？ - 反正不是你說的
It's Frank.
就是弗蘭克
He's appointed himself judge, jury and executioner.
他把自己當法官，陪審團 還有執行官
- He's not Judge Judy and executioner. - He is!
- 他不是法官，陪審團或者執行官 - 他就是
- You've gotta help me take him down. - I can't.
- 你必須幫我拿下他 - 不行
He's my dad. Take my car.
他是我老爸 開我的車
Go back to London. There's nothing you can do.
回倫敦去吧 沒別的辦法了
I can come back.
我會回來的
They'll make it disappear. Who are they gonna believe?
警車也能被他們蒸發掉 大家會信誰？
My dad, or a loony London police officer.
我老爸還是發瘋的倫敦警察？
But it won't be just me, will it?
你不會讓我孤軍奮戰的對不對？
We can do it together. You and me. Partners.
我們可以一起 你和我一起來，搭檔
Forget it, Nicholas. It's Sandford.
不可能的，瘦子 這裡是沙福德
Sir? Sir?
先生？先生？
- Is there anything I can do for you? - No.
- 還需要些什麼嗎？ - 不要了
This is something I have to do myself.
剩下的得由我自己來
Another beautiful day in God's country.
上帝又賜了一個好天氣
Danny?
胖子？
It's...
是…
Mum!
老媽！
What you gonna do?
你想怎麼樣？
Just walk in and arrest the whole village?
大搖大擺的拘捕所有村民？
Not exactly.
可別小看我
Oh, Sergeant Angel? Someone from London called for you.
天使警官 倫敦有人打電話找你
I'll tell them you'll ring them back.
我叫他們遲點再打好了
- Well, that's funny. - What's that?
- 真好玩 - 什麼好玩？
I didn't know we had a mounted division.
我們這裡竟然有騎警
Nobody tells me nothing.
沒人跟我講過
Wanna do something useful?
要不要來幫忙？
AMANDA: Annette, that Sergeant Angel's back. Check out his horse.
安妮特，天使警官回來 快看他的坐騎
ANNETTE: (WHISPERS) Roger that!
收到
- It's... - Angel.
- 他… - 天使
Morning.
早
That's what I'm talking about.
這才像話
Still feel like you're missing out?
還覺得自己白混了？
Fascist!
法西斯主義者！
Hag!
母夜叉！
Stop! Stop this, please!
住手！請住手！
Let us stop this mindless violence.
讓我們停止這無畏的鬥爭
Nicholas, my son.
尼古拉斯，孩子
You may not be a man of God, but surely you're a man of peace.
就算你不是上帝的子民 你也應該崇尚和平
I may not be a man of God, Reverend, but I know right, and I know wrong,
我雖不是上帝的子民，牧師 但我分辨是與非
and I have the good grace to know which is which.
承蒙天賜，我還能分辨好與壞
No!
不要！
Jesus Christ!
耶和華啊！
Nicholas! Nicholas!
瘦子！瘦子！
I thought you was a goner.
我以為你掛了
Drop your weapons!
放下武器！
- Dr. Hatcher, no! - Shut up, Danny.
- 孵化器醫生，不要啊 - 閉嘴，胖子
I brought you into this world, I think it's rather fitting
你是我接生的 我想也應該有我…
I should be the one to take you out of it.
送你去見閻王爺
You and your interfering little friend.
還有你愛惹麻煩的小朋友
Now...
好了…
drop them.
放下武器
- You're a doctor, deal with it. - Yeah, motherfucker.
- 你是醫生，自己解決 - 哼，老屄樣子
- Danny, let's roll. - What you thinking?
- 胖子，我們繼續 - 下一站是哪兒？
Pub?
酒館？
Roy!
羅伊!
Somebody call the police!
警察快來啊！
Freeze!
不許動！
Officers, arrest that man.
警官們，逮捕那個人
- Danny, step away from the Sergeant. - No, Dad.
- 丹尼，站到一邊去 - 不，老爸
Danny, you'll do as you're told.
丹尼，照我說的去做
I'm not taking orders from you anymore.
我不要再聽你使喚了
- Officers, arrest these men! - Wait, wait!
- 警官們，逮捕他們！ - 等等！
You can arrest us if you like.
你們可以想逮捕我們…
You can throw us in prison and go back to being blind, submissive slaves.
抓我們去坐牢 然後白白給人做奴隸？
Or you can be real police officers,
還是做真正的警察
and help us bring an end to this absurd story.
和我們一起結束這荒謬的殘局
What the fuck is he on about?
你他媽在嘀咕什麼？
Fuck are you on about?
他媽的啥？
Have you ever wondered why the crime rate in Sandford is so low?
你們就沒想過沙福德的犯罪率低…
- And yet the accident rate, it's so high? - No. Yeah. What?
- 而意外事故發生率高的原因嗎？ - 沒，有，什麼？
You've been brainwashed, Tony.
你們都被洗腦了，托尼
Brainwashed into naivety by an old man with a murderous obsession.
被個老謀殺狂洗成白癡了
- This is ridiculous. - No, it's not, Dad. It's very unridiculous.
- 荒唐 - 是真的，老爸，不荒唐
And it's only now that I'm starting to realise how unridiculous it all is.
我現在才意識到這一切 一點都不荒唐
Silence, Danny!
閉嘴，丹尼！
- Think of your mother. - Mum is dead, Dad.
- 想想你母親 - 老媽已經死了，老爸
For the first time in my life, you know, I'm glad.
有生以來我第一次為她的死感到慶幸
If she could see what you've become,
要是讓她看到你現在的樣子
I think she'd probably kill herself all over again.
她肯定會再越崖一次的
Sorry, I am completely lost.
抱歉，我聽糊塗了
Sandford is a lie, Doris.
沙福德是個騙局，多瑞絲
For the last 20 years, the village has been controlled by Frank and the NWA.
這20年來 弗蘭克和NWA掌控了這個小村
They've lulled everyone into thinking this is a perfect village
表面上，他們告訴大家 這是一個完美的鄉村
and killed anyone who's threatened to change that.
背地裡卻幹掉任何違背他們的人
I reckon he's got something there.
他說得有點道理
He says, "He reckons you got something there."
他說「他說得有點道理」
I know.
我知道
You're not seriously gonna believe this man, are you?
你們不會真的信了吧？
Are you? He isn't even from round here.
相信他？ 他都不是個本地人
Maybe it's time to give it up, sir.
回頭是岸啊，長官
You incompetent flatfoots!
你們這群臭條子
Officer Walker, stay here with Saxon and hold everything down.
步行者警員，和撒克遜守在這裡 封鎖現場
Fair enough.
沒問題
Officers, let's go.
同志們，我們走
- What about Dad? - He'll come round again.
- 老爸怎麼辦？ - 他會回來的
Want anything from the shop?
要不要去另一家店？
- What you thinking? - Well...
想到辦法沒？
We should strike now, while we've got the element of surprise.
現在進攻就可以製造突襲的優勢
Longer we wait, more time they've got to mobilise.
等久了，對方就有準備
I say we go in through the front entrance, take the place aisle by aisle.
我建議直接從正門闖入 逐個佔領所有通道
They won't be expecting that.
攻其不備
Very good. What he said.
很好，就這樣
My, my. Here come the fuzz.
哎呀，警察來了
- Maybe they're not here. - Wait here.
- 或許他們不在這裡 - 在這兒候命
- Don't go in on your own. - Don't worry, he knows what he's doing.
-  你一個人不行的 - 沒事，他知道該做什麼
Okay. They're in.
我沒事，他們在裡面
You deal with the store. I'll deal with the trolley boy.
你們處理店內的，我處理推車男
No, listen. Wait, wait, wait, Michael, wait, listen to me. Listen, listen.
聽著，等等，邁克 聽我說，聽好
Is this what you really, really want?
你真的，真的想打架？
Yarp.
好的
Suit yourself.
那隨便你了
FISHER: Go, go, go.
上，上，上
Oh, come on.
拜託
Andy!
安迪！
It's all right, Andy. It's just Bolognese!
沒事，安迪 只是牛肉麵番茄醬！
- How's Lurch? - He's in the freezer.
- 傻大個呢？ - 在冷藏櫃裡
- Did you say, "Cool off"? - No, I didn't say anything, actually.
- 你說他冷靜了點沒？ - 沒，我好像啥都沒說
Shame.
真可惜
There was a bit earlier on that you missed
其實之前你不知道
when I distracted him with the cuddly monkey.
我用抱抱猴分散他注意力 說「遊戲結束了」
You're off the fucking chain!
你太亂來了
- What's the situation? - Two blokes and a fuckload of cutlery.
- 情況如何？ - 2名目標還有一大箱刀具
What do you reckon?
怎麼辦？
Idea.
這麼辦
Good work, everyone.
幹的好，各位
- Nice one, Doris. - Nothing like a bit of girl on girl.
- 厲害，多瑞絲 - 同性相斥嘛
Fruit attack!
水果戰
Can you handle this, Sergeant Fisher? We're gonna go after the big boss.
你能處理嗎，漁夫警官？ 我們去解決大老闆
We're on it, Sergeant.
沒問題，警官
- Danny, let's rock. - Angel!
- 胖子，我們上 - 天使！
Don't go being a twat now.
別再當廢柴了
I wouldn't give you the satisfaction.
不會讓你失望的
- We should get down there. - How?
我們下去追
Skip.
- 怎麼下？ - 跳樓
- Head them off? - Fuck, yeah.
- 要去追他們？ - 操他媽的對！
- I'll drive. - Shotgun! Punch that shit!
- 我來開車 - 用獵槍，打他幾個大窟窿
(SIREN WAILING)
[評委們後面的橫幅] 祝你們好運，沙福德 「年度最佳鄉村」
Swan!
天鵝！
Stay back! Or the ginger nut gets it!
退後！ 不然吃子彈的就是這小子
You little fucker!
你這小屄樣子！
Get out of my village!
滾出我的村子！
It's not your village anymore.
這村子不再是你的了
- You did good, kid. - Ta.
- 幹的好，孩子 - 謝謝
- What's your name? - Aaron A. Aaronson.
- 你叫什麼名字？ - 艾倫·艾·艾倫的兒子
Sorry?
什麼？
Angel!
天使！
It's over, Danny.
結束了，胖子
It's over.
都結束了
This really hurts.
痛死我了
I'm going to need some ice-cream.
我要吃冰激凌
Yeah, well, don't worry. There's plenty of ice-cream at the station.
別擔心，局裡有很多
Isn't that right, Danny?
對不對，胖子？
Stay back!
退後！
- Pack it in, Frank, you silly bastard! - Now, now.
- 住手吧，弗蘭克，你這老糊塗 - 你聽我的
We don't want any more bloodshed.
我們誰都不想傷害對方
Frank, this whole thing started because you lost somebody you loved.
弗蘭克，你做的這一切 都因為你失去了你愛的人
Don't expect me to believe you'd let it end the same way.
我不信你會以 失去兒子來結束這一切
I'll tell you how this is gonna end!
我來告訴你我要怎麼結束！
I feel like I should say something smart.
我不知道該怎麼說了
You don't have to say anything at all.
你什麼都不用說
Satisfactory conclusion to the whole operation.
整個行動非常成功
Now, my perfect Sunday would begin with...
而我理想中的星期日應該是…
CHIEF INSPECTOR: What do you say, Nicholas?
你覺得如何，尼古拉斯？
We... We... We have been trying to reach you for days.
我們…我們… 我們這幾天一直在找你
- Yeah, well, I've been kind of busy. - SERGEANT: We need you back.
- 是啊，我最近有點忙 - 我們需要你
The figures have gone a little squiffy in your absence, it has to be said.
說實話 你的缺席讓犯罪率漲過頭了點
Come back to London.
回倫敦吧
Sandford's hardly a fitting place for such an exceptional officer.
沙福德配不上你這樣出色的警官
Yeah, well, the thing is, sir.
這個，問題是…長官，
I kind of like it here.
我挺喜歡這裡的
Besides, we have to do a considerable amount of paperwork.
還有，這裡有很多文檔工作要解決
FISHER: Well, good job we've got the manpower, Andy?
幹的好 還好有足夠的人力，安迪
Well, official vocab guidelines state that we say "staffing," not "manpower,"
官方指南寫的是 「警署職員」，不是「人力」
'cause "manpower's" a bit sexist.
感覺「人力」有點男性主義化
You don't mind a bit of manpower do you, Doris?
你介意用「人力」嗎，多瑞絲？
Oh, dirty bastard!
色狼！
You cheeky fucker!
日趴你！
You know what you are?
你算什麼東西？
A bloody busybody!
好管閒事的畜牲
No!
不！
Oh, God, no!
上帝，不是吧
ANGEL: Danny!
胖子！
Oh, God.
天哪
Hold on, Danny, just hold on.
堅持住，胖子，堅持
Hold on, it's gonna be fine. It's gonna be fine.
堅持住，會沒事的 一定會沒事的
Just hang on, hang on!
堅持，堅持住
Everything's gonna be fine.
一切都會沒事的
Hope these are okay.
希望你喜歡這些花 [悼念親愛的黃油男]
Yeah. They're lovely.
嗯，很漂亮
- Any officers near the church? - Go ahead, Doris.
- 城堡附近有警員嗎？ - 請說，多瑞絲
Chief, we've had a report of some hippy types
警長，有人報告說一些西皮乞丐…
messing with the recycling bins at the supermarket.
在超市的回收場搗亂
- Leave it with us. - Righto.
- 我們去處理 - 好的
Sergeant Butterman, little hand says it's time to rock and roll.
黃油男警官 該我們登場了
Bring the noise.
拉起警報